<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <RecipeDetails id="1" recipeName="Aloo Gobi Paratha" serves="3-4" ingredients="FOR THE WHOLE WHEAT DOUGH: \n 2.5 to 3 cups whole wheat flour/atta \n 1 to 2 tsp oil or ghee \n Water as required \n Salt as required \n \n  FOR THE STUFFING: \n 2 cups grated cauliflower \n 1.5 cups mashed potatoes \n 1 to 2 green chilies, finely chopped \n Red chili powder \n Punjabi garam masala powder \n Salt as required \n Ghee or oil for frying the parathas, as required \n Flour for dusting \n" method="PREPARING THE DOUGH:\n 1) Mix salt with the whole wheat flour. you can even sieve the whole wheat flour along with the salt.\n 2) Add ghee/oil and water to the flour. first mix and then begin to knead the dough.\n 3) The dough has to be kneaded well and should be soft.\n 4) If the dough feels dense or dry, then add some more water and continue to knead. cover the dough and let it rest for about 20-30 minutes.\n\n  FOR PREPARING THE PARATHA FILLING:\n 1) Rinse and slice the gobi/cauliflower into 2 parts or 4 parts.\n 2) Heat water with some salt it comes to a vigorous boil.\n 3) Add the sliced cauliflower and switch off the flame. cover the pan and keep aside for 15-20 minutes.\n 4) Meantime rinse the potatoes and boil or steam them in a pressure cooker or steamer. they should be well cooked and falling apart. so that you can mash them easily. once they are warm or you can handle the heat, peel and mash them.\n 5) Now drain the cauliflower and wipe then dry.\n 6) Grate the cauliflower and take all of it in a bowl\n 7) Add the mashed potatoes. add chopped green chilies. mix well and keep aside.\n\n  PREPARING THE STUFFED PARATHAS:\n 1) Pinch two small or medium sized balls from the dough.\n 2) Roll them in your palms. dust them with flour and roll into a small circles.\n 3) Place a few tbsp of the filling on one of the dough circle.\n 4) Keep in mind that the filling should not be too less or too much.\n 5) Sprinkle 2 to 3 pinches of salt, garam masala powder and red chili powder evenly on the stuffing.\n 6) Sprinkle some flour on the filling. this helps in absorbing the moisture and when rolling, the paratha does not break or tear.\n 7) Lightly sprinkle some wheat flour and roll the aloo paratha gently into a diameter of 6-8 inches.\n 8) Place the stuffed aloo paratha on a hot tava or griddle. when one side has slightly browned, flip the paratha.\n 9) Spread or brush some oil/ghee ( i usually add 1 to 2 tsp oil or ghee) on the browned side.\n 10)Flip again and brush oil (again 1 to 2 tsp oil or ghee) on the other side.\n 11)Flip once or twice, till you see golden spots on the aloo gobi paratha and they look crisp and well cooked.\n 12)Serve the aloo gobi paratha hot with fresh yogurt, mango pickle or lemon pickle topped with some butter.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="2" recipeName="Dosa(Made with rice floor)" serves="3-4" ingredients="1.25 to 1.5 cups rice flour\n ¾ cup urad dal flour/husked black gram flour\n 2.5 cups water or add as required\n Salt as required\n Oil as required\n" method="1) add both the rice and urad dal flour into a mixing bowl.\n 2) pour water and mix well. the batter has to be smooth and without any lumps and evenly mixed. the consistency should be that of a thick batter but still flowing.\n 3) pour the batter from the mixing bowl in another bowl. cover and allow to ferment at room temperature overnight for 9-10 hours or more if required.\n 4) once the batter is fermented well, then add salt to the dosa batter and mix well.\n 5) heat an iron griddle or tava. smear with oil lightly. take a spoon or ladle with the batter and gently start spreading the dosa in circular rounds. if using non stick pan, then avoid smearing oil on the pan. since you won't be able to spread the dosa batter properly on the non stick pan.\n 6) drizzle oil on the top and sides and let one side cook.\n 7) when one side of dosa is browned, flip and cook the other side.\n 8) fold the dosa and serve hot with coconut chutney or vegetable sambar.\n 9) make dosa in the same way with the batter.\n 10)the leftover dosa batter can be refrigerated and used within 4 to 5 days.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="3" recipeName="Gojju Avalakki" serves="5" ingredients="Poha - 2 1/2 cups, thick variety (beaten rice/atukulu/aval)\n Water - 2 cups\n Jaggery - 1 1/2 tbsps, grated (can reduce or increase according to individual preference)\n Tamarind paste - 1 1/2 tbsps\n Rasam powder - 2 heaped tsps, home made or store bought\n Salt to taste\n Coriander leaves - 2 tbsps, finely chopped\n Fresh coconut - 2 tbsps, grated (optional)\n Dry roast and grind to a coarse powder: (OPTIONAL)\n Black pepper corns - 7-8\n Sesame seeds - 1 heaped tablespoon (til/nuvvulu)\n\n  FOR POPPU/TADKA/TEMPERING:\n Oil - 1 tbsp\n Mustard seeds - 1 tsp\n Urad dal - 1 tsp (split black gram dal/minappa pappu)\n Curry leaves - 1 sprig\n Asafoetida - large pinch\n Peanuts - fistful, roasted\n" method="1) Grind the beaten rice or poha coarsely like semolina. Wash the ground beaten rice and drain completely. Keep aside.\n 2) Heat a stainless steel vessel, add 2 cups of water, grated jaggery, tamarind paste, rasam powder and salt to taste. Bring to a boil and simmer till the jaggery is completely dissolved, approx 3-4 mts. Turn off flame and allow to cool a bit, approx 7-8 mts.\n 3) Sprinkle 1 1/2 cups of the prepared tamarind water over the wet poha, a little at at time and toss the contents such that its mixed thoroughly with the coarsely ground beaten rice. Sprinkle the remaining tamarind water such that the beaten rice is well coated with it. It should appear like a crumbled mixture.\n 4) Place lid over the beaten rice mixture and allow it to sit for 15 mts. After 15 mts, if you feel that the mixture is too dry, add the remaining tamarind water and toss the contents and allow to sit for another 15 mts.\n 5) Heat oil in a small pan and once it is hot, add the mustard seeds and allow them to splutter. Add the urad dal and allow it to turn red. Add asafoetida, turmeric powder, roasted peanuts and curry leaves and saute for few seconds.\n 6) Crumble the beaten rice mixture into the tempering and mix thoroughly. Place lid and cook for 4-5 mts. Add the black pepper and sesame seeds powder, adjust salt and add more jaggery if required. Mix well, Turn off flame.\n 7) Remove to a serving bowl and garnish with fresh coconut and fresh coriander leaves.\n\n  TIPS\n 1) You can use a mix of 1 tsp of rasam powder and 1 tsp of sambar powder OR use 2 tsps of sambar powder instead of rasam powder.\n 2) The additon of the ground mix of roasted sesame seeds and pepper corns is optional.\n 3) Peanuts, tamarind and jaggery are essential ingredients for this recipe.\n 4) If you find that the mixture is dry after following Step 6 above, sprinkle some more water and mix. Place lid and cook for a a mt or two.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="4" recipeName="Onion Potato Poha" serves="2-3" ingredients="1.5 cups poha, thick variety (flattened or parched rice)\n ¼ to ½ tsp turmeric powder\n 1 or 2 green chilies, chopped\n 2 tbsp peanuts\n 1 medium potato, chopped into small cubes\n 1 medium onion, finely chopped\n ¾th tsp mustard seeds\n ¾th tsp cumin seeds\n 8 to 9 curry leaves\n 2 to 3 tbsp grated coconut\n 1 tbsp chopped coriander leaves\n 2 to 2.5 tbsp oil\n Sugar as required ( i usually add up to 1 tsp of sugar)\n Salt as required\n" method="1) Pick the poha first. rinse the poha in clean running water in a strainer.\n 2) Make sure that you do not rinse it too much or else it breaks and gets mushy. while rinsing, the poha absorbs enough water and it becomes soft.\n 3) The poha must become soft but remain intact, whole and separate.\n 4) If the poha does not become soft, sprinkle few drops of water on the poha in the strainer till they get softened.\n 5) Sprinkle the turmeric powder, sugar and salt in the poha. Gently mix.\n 6) Roast the peanuts in a small pan till they become crunchy and keep aside.\n 7) Also peel the potatoes and chop them into small cubes.\n 8) In a kadai, heat oil. saute the potatoes in medium hot oil till light golden and crisp. keep aside.\n 9) In the same kadai, add the mustard seeds to the hot oil. when they splutter, add the cumin seeds. When the cumin seeds sizzle, add the onions. saute the onions till they become translucent and soften.\n 10)Now add the curry leaves, green chili and roasted peanuts. saute for a minute.\n 11)Add the fried potatoes and then the poha. mix gently with the rest of the mixture.\n 12)Saute the entire poha mixture for 2-3 minutes on a low flame, stirring gently in between. taste the poha and if required add more salt and sugar.\n 13)Switch off the flame and cover the pan tightly with a lid for the poha to get steamed for a few minutes.\n 14)Remove the lid and garnish the poha with chopped coriander/cilantro leaves and grated fresh coconut.\n 15)Serve kanda batata poha hot with chopped lemon pieces. the lemon juice has to be squeezed on to the poha before eating it.\n 16)Alternatively, you could also do this method. once the poha is done, sprinkle approx 1 to 2 tsp lime juice on the kanda batata poha. mix it with the poha and then garnish it with coconut and cilantro leaves.\n\n  NOTES\n Adding sugar is optional. you can skip it completely if you don't prefer a slightly sweet taste in the kanda batata poha.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="5" recipeName="Masala Dosa" serves="10-12 dosa" ingredients="FOR THE DOSA BATTER:\n 1 cup regular rice\n 1 cup parboiled rice\n ½ cup spilt black lentils or urad dal\n ¼ cup poha/flattened rice\n ¼ tsp fenugreek seeds (methi)\n Salt to taste\n Water as required\n\n  FOR THE MASALA - POTATO FILLING:\n 4-5 potatoes/aloo\n 10-12 cashewnuts/kaju (optional)\n 10-12 curry leaves/kadi patta\n 1 tbsp chana dal/bengal gram\n 3 onions sliced or chopped\n ½ tsp mustard seeds/rai\n 1 tsp cumin seeds/jeera\n 1 or 2 chopped green chillies/hari mirch\n 1 or 1.5 tsp chopped ginger or grated ginger\n 2 tbsp chopped coriander leaves/dhania\n ½ tsp turmeric powder/haldi\n a pinch of asafoetida/hing\n 3 tsp oil or ghee\n Salt\n" method="PREPARING THE DOSA BATTER:\n 1) Rinse the rice and urad dal separately first.\n 2) Soak the parboiled rice, regular rice and poha in a bowl or pan.\n 3) In another bowl soak the urad dal-methi in enough water\n 4) Grind the urad dal with methi to a fine and fluffy batter.\n 5) Grind the rice and poha to a smooth batter.\n 6) Mix both the rice and urad dal batter with salt.\n 7) Cover and let the batter ferment for 8-9 hours.\n\n  PREPARING THE POTATO FILLING-SABZI:\n 1) Heat oil or ghee. Fry cashew nuts and keep aside.\n 2) Splutter the mustard seeds. add cumin seeds and chana dal.\n 3) Fry the chana dal well. Now add the onions and curry leaves.\n 4) Fry the onions till they become soft. Add the green chilies and ginger.\n 5) Add the turmeric powder and asafoetida. Mix well.\n 6) Now add the boiled chopped potatoes. Add the fried cashew nuts and salt\n 7) Cook for 2-3 minutes stirring well. Add chopped coriander leaves. Stir and keep aside.\n\n  PREPARING THE MASALA DOSA:\n 1) Heat a flat pan or a flat non-stick pan. Smear some oil if using an iron pan or griddle. don't smear oil on a non stick pan, as then you won't be able to spread the dosa batter.\n 2) Spread the dosa batter in a circular way on the pan. Add some oil on top\n 3) Flip and cook the other side. Flip again.\n 4) Spread the potato sabzi filling on one side of the dosa.\n 5) Cover with the other half and let the dosa cook for 15-30 seconds.\n 6) Serve masala dosa hot with coconut chutney and sambar\n\n NOTES\n 1) If you are unable to spread the batter on the pan, then add some water to the dosa batter. this will help you in spreading the batter evenly on the pan. \n 2) To get golden brown dosa, the pan should be hot. But the flip side is that if the pan is very hot, then you cannot spread the dosa batter nicely. Either sprinkle water on the pan and then wipe it. This brings down the temperature of the pan. Do this method on an iron pan. Don't do this on a non stick pan. It might affect the non stick coating. \n 3) If using a non stick pan than as soon as one dosa is done, reduce the flame. Spread the dosa batter on the pan. now increase the flame and let the dosa cook.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="6" recipeName="Masala Idli" serves="4" ingredients="8 left over idlis\n 2 slit green chilies\n 1? ginger grated\n 1 onion, finely chopped\n 1 large tomato, finely chopped\n 1 tbsp coriander leaves, finely chopped\n 1/4 tsp turmeric pwd\n 1/2 tsp red chili pwd\n 1 tsp coriander pwd\n 1/2 tsp saunf/fennel seeds pwd\n pinch of garam masala pwd (optional)\n 1/2 tbsp lemon juice (optional)\n 1 tbsp oil\n Salt\n\n  FOR TEMPERING:\n 1 tsp mustard seeds\n 12-15 curry leaves\n" method="1) Heat oil in a cooking vessel, add the mustard seeds and let them splutter. Add the curry leaves and saute till a nice aroma emanates the kitchen.\n 2) Add the green chilies and ginger and saute for few secs.\n 3) Add the chopped onions and saute on medium heat for 3-4 mts. Add turmeric pwd, red chili pwd, coriander pwd, saunf pwd and garam masala pwd. Mix well.\n 4) Add the chopped tomatoes and saute for 5 mts till oil separates. Add the crumbled idlis and mix. Saute for 2 mts. Add lemon juice and mix. Turn off heat.\n 5) Garnish with chopped coriander leaves. Serve warm.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="7" recipeName="Masala Paddu" serves="2-3" ingredients="2 cups idli batter\n 1 medium size onion, finely chopped or minced\n 1 or 2 green chilies, finely chopped\n ½ inch ginger, finely chopped or grated\n a pinch of asafoetida/hing (optional)\n ½ tsp crushed black pepper (optional)\n ¼ tsp red chili powder/lal mirch powder\n 2 tbsp chopped curry leaves\n ½ cup grated coconut\n Salt if required\n" method="1) Mix all the ingredients in the idli batter.\n 2) Add salt if the idli batter does not have salt previously added to it. stir well.\n 3) Heat the paniyaram chatti. add a few drops of oil.\n 4) Pour spoonful of the batter ¾ of the paniyaram mould.\n 5) Allow the batter to cook for 2-3 minutes on a low or medium flame.\n 6) Turn each paniyaram with the help of a wooden skewer or spoon.\n 7) Now allow the other side to get cooked and crisp.\n 8) Turn once or twice for uniform cooking.\n 9) Remove and keep in a casserole so that they stay warm.\n 10)These masala paniyaram are also good as tiffin box snack or picnic snack.\n 11)Serve masala paniyaram with coconut chutney or sambar.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="8" recipeName="Methi Thepla" serves="11- 12 theplas" ingredients="1 cup whole wheat flour/atta\n 1 cup gram flour/besan\n 1 cup chopped fresh fenugreek (methi) leaves\n 1 tsp cumin powder or whole cumin\n 1 tsp coriander powder (dhania powder)\n ½ tsp turmeric (haldi)\n 1 tsp red chili powder (lal mirch powder)\n 1 tsp green chilli-ginger paste (hari mirch - adrak paste)\n 2 tbsp oil\n 1 to 2 tbsp water or 1 to 2 tbsp curd/yogurt\n Salt as required\n Oil for frying\n" method="1) Mix all the ingredients except water.\n 2) Start kneading without adding water first.\n 3) The methi (fenugreek) leaves leave a lot of water.\n 4) Just add 1 tbsp or 2 tbsp water if required.\n 5) If the dough become sticky, then just add some more wheat flour.\n 6) Keep the dough aside for 15-20 minutes covered with a kitchen towel.\n 7) Now make medium sized balls from the dough.\n 8) Roll each ball thinly into flat discs.\n 9) Heat a frying pan or tava.\n 10)Place the thepla on the pan.\n 11)When one side is half cooked, flip it.\n 12)Apply ½ or 1 tsp oil on the cooked side.\n 13)Now again flip and apply ½ or 1 tsp oil on the other side.\n 14)Flip again twice.\n 15)Once the thepla is cooked as well as browned, remove from the pan.\n 16)Make all the theplas this way.\n 17)Stack them up and keep in a roti basket or in covered in a kitchen napkin.\n 18)Serve methi theplas with mango or lime pickles, or potato sabzi.\n 19)You can also have methi theplas plain with indian chai or tea.\n\n  NOTES\n Instead of water you can also add curd. for frying instead of oil you can use ghee if you want." />
    <RecipeDetails id="9" recipeName="Misal Pav" serves="4-5" ingredients="FOR THE USAL (SPROUTS CURRY):\n 3.5 cups moth means sprouts/matki sprouts or mixed bean sprouts - i used about 1 cup of moth beans\n 2 small to medium potatoes, cubed\n 1 large or medium onion, finely chopped\n 1 or 2 green chilies, chopped (hari mircj)\n 3 to 4 garlic/lahsun + 1 inch ginger/adrak - crushed in a mortar-pestle to a fine paste\n 1 tsp mustard seeds (rai or sarson)\n 1 tsp cumin seeds (jeera)\n 10 to 12 curry leaves (kadi patta)\n 1 to 1.5 tbsp goda masala/kala masala\n ½ tsp turmeric powder (haldi)\n ½ tsp red chili powder (lal mirch powder)\n 1 tsp coriander powder (dhania powder)\n 1 tsp cumin powder (jeera powder)\n 1.5 tsp seedless tamarind soaked in ? or ½ cup water or 2 to 3 kokums\n ¾ to 1 cup water or as required\n 3 tbsp oil\n Salt as required\n\n  FOR THE MISAL PAV:\n 8 to 10 pav/bread buns or bread slices\n 1 cup finely chopped onion\n 1 cup finely chopped tomatoes (optional)\n 1 cup thick sev or farsan/chiwda (fried savory snack mixture)\n 1 lemon, quartered or diced\n ? cup coriander leaves (dhania patta)\n ½ cup curd/yogurt, beaten (optional)\n" method="PREPARING THE USAL:\n 1) Rinse the moth bean sprouts first in running water.\n 2) Drain and then add the sprouts, cubed potatoes, ¼ tsp turmeric powder, salt in a pressure cooker. the water should be covering the matki sprouts about ½ inch above. if using mixed bean sprouts, you will have to add more water.\n 3) Pressure cook for 2 to 3 whistles.\n 4) In a small bowl soak the tamarind in ? or ½ cup warm water for 25 to 30 mins.\n 5) Squeeze the tamarind and extract the pulp. keep the tamarind pulp aside.\n 6) Heat oil in another pan.\n 7) Crackle the mustard seeds first.\n 8) Then add the cumin and saute for some seconds till the cumin gets golden.\n 9) Add the chopped onions and saute till translucent.\n 10)Then add the curry leaves, ginger-garlic paste and green chilies\n 11)Stir and saute till the raw aroma of ginger-garlic goes away.\n 12)Add the remaining ¼ tsp turmeric powder, coriander powder, cumin powder, red chili powder and goda masala.\n 13)Stir and then add the tamarind pulp.\n 14)Saute till the raw aroma of the tamarind goes away.\n 15)Drain the pressure cooked matki sprouts and potatoes and add them to the tamarind pulp.\n 16)Stir and add ¾ to 1 cup water or more water if required.\n 17)Season with salt and simmer the usal for 8 to 10 mins on a low flame with occasional stirrings.\n 18)Lastly garnish with coriander leaves.\n 19)If you want you can also add sugar or jaggery.\n\n  ASSEMBLING THE MISAL PAV:\n 1) Whilst the usal is simmering, you can prep the toppings for the misal pav.\n 2) Finely chop the onions and tomatoes. keep aside.\n 3) Take the steaming usal in 4 to 5 bowls.\n 4) In each bowl of usal, first add the chopped onions and tomatoes.\n 5) Then top usal with chopped coriander leaves.\n 6) Squeeze a few drops of lemon juice.\n 7) Then top it with farsan or chiwda.\n 8) Serve the misal bowl in a plate with pav buns and slices of lemon, chopped onion and mix farsan/sev/chiwda.\n 9) Enjoy the misal pav.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="10" recipeName="Paneer Bhurji" serves="2-3" ingredients="200 gms paneer, crumbled (cottage cheese)\n 1 medium sized tomato/tamatar, finely chopped\n 1 medium sized onion/pyaaz, finely chopped\n 1 green chilli/hari mirch, finely chopped\n 1 finely chopped ginger/adrak\n ¼ tsp turmeric powder/haldi\n ¼ tsp chilly powder (optional)\n ¼ tsp garam masala powder (optional)\n ¼ tsp cumin seeds/jeera (optional)\n Salt as required\n 2 tbsp oil, ghee, butter or white butter\n A few coriander/dhania leaves for garnishing (optional)\n" method="1) Crumble the paneer/cottage cheese and keep aside\n 2) Heat oil or ghee or butter in a pan.\n 3) Add cumin seeds first if you are using them. once they get fried, add onions. when the onions become transparent, add chopped ginger and chilly.\n 4) Fry the ginger for 15-20 seconds.\n 5) Then add tomatoes and cook till they become soft. you can add a little salt so that the tomatoes get cooked faster.\n 6) Now add all the spice powders. fry for 30 seconds.\n 7) Finally, add the crumbled paneer and let it cook for 1-2 minutes.\n 8) Don't cook the paneer for a long time as they harden and loose their softness.\n 9) Serve paneer bhurji with bread toast. you can also serve paneer bhurji with rotis, plain parathas or as a side dish.\n 10)The paneer bhurji can also be garnished with chopped coriander leaves.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="11" recipeName="Puri Bhaji" serves="3-4" ingredients="FOR PURI\n Whole wheat flour or atta: 3 cups\n 1 tsp melted ghee or oil (optional)\n Salt as required\n Water as required\n Oil for deep frying\n\n  FOR BHAJI\n 4 medium sized potatoes\n 1 large onion, chopped\n 1 green chili, chopped\n 1 tsp mustard\n 1 tsp cumin\n 1.5 tsp urad dal/black gram\n ¾ cup water\n ½ tsp turmeric powder\n a pinch of asafoetida/hing\n ½ to ¾ cup chopped coriander/cilantro leaves\n 1 inch ginger, finely chopped\n 12-15 curry leaves\n 2 or 3 tbsp peanut oil or sunflower oil\n Salt as required\n" method="PURI METHOD:\n 1) Sieve the whole wheat flour with salt. add melted ghee or oil.\n 2) Add little water at a time and knead well to form a dough. the dough should not be soft but a little stiff and tight.\n 3) Divide the dough into small or medium pieces – about 12-14.\n 4) Make into medium sized or slightly small balls and roll out into small circles.\n 5) Heat oil in a deep frying pan or kadai.\n 6) When the oil is sufficiently hot then add one poori at a time and fry gently pressing down with the frying spoon or slotted spoon in a circular motion.\n 7) Turn over when puffed up and fry the poori till golden brown.\n 8) Serve Poori hot with a vegetable curry or sweet dishes like suji ka halva ( known as sheera in maharashtra ) or aam ras or aloo tamatar ki sabzi.\n\n  BHAJI METHOD:\n 1) Boil the potatoes till they are cooked completely.\n 2) Once they are warm, peel them and chop.\n 3) In a pan, heat oil.\n 4) Add cumin, mustard and urad dal.\n 5) Fry till the mustard crackles and starts making sound and the urad dal begins to turn brown.\n 6) Add the chopped onion.\n 7) Fry till they become soft and transparent.\n 8) Now add the ginger and green chilies.\n 9) Fry for a minute.\n 10)Add the curry leaves.\n 11)Stir and fry for some seconds.\n 12)Add the turmeric and asafoetida.\n 13)Stir and fry for some seconds.\n 14)Don't burn the turmeric.\n 15)Next, add the chopped potatoes, half of the coriander leaves.\n 16)Stir. now add ¾ water and salt.\n 17)Stir and cover the pan.\n 18)Let the bhaji simmer for 5-6 minutes on a low flame.\n 19)There should be some moisture in the bhaji and it should not be very dry.\n 20)Add the remaining coriander leaves.\n 21)Stir and serve batata bhaji hot with pooris, chapatis or dosa.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="12" recipeName="Semiya Pulao" serves="4" ingredients="Vermicelli - 2 cups, semiya - roast in 2 tsps ghee on low to medium flame till golden brown\n Onion - 1, large, sliced\n Carrot - 1, medium sized, peeled and cubed\n French beans - 5, nip ends and cut into 1/2 pieces\n Potato - 1, medium sized, peeled and cubed\n Green peas - fistful (optional)\n Mint leaves - 12-15 leaves\n Coriander leaves for garnish\n Cloves - 2\n Cinnamon stick - 1\n Green cardamom - 1\n Bay leaf - 1, optional\n Cumin seeds - 1/2 tsp, optional\n Oil - 1 tbsp\n Ghee - 1 tbsp, heaped\n Water - 3 1/2 cups (hot)\n Salt to taste\n\n  MAKE A PASTE:\n Fresh coconut - 2 tbsps\n Fennel seeds - 1 tsp\n Ginger - 1/2 piece\n Green chilies - 2-3 (adjust to suit spice level)\n Coriander leaves - 2 tbsps, finely chopped\n " method="1) Heat a heavy bottomed vessel, add ghee+oil, once its hot, add cumin seeds and allow to brown. Add cinnamon stick, cardamom, cloves and bay leaf and saute for few seconds.\n 2) Add sliced onions and saute for 4 mts. Add mint leaves and ground paste and saute for 3 mts.\n 3) Add mixed vegetables and saute 8-10 mts. Remove lid and mix well.\n 4) Add the roasted vermicelli and green peas (if using) mix well. Add 3 1/2 cups of hot water and bring to a boil. Reduce flame, place lid and cook till the semiya and vegetables are cooked.\n 5) Remove lid, mix well. Remove the semiya pulao to a serving bowl and garnish with fresh coriander leaves.\n\n  TIPS:\n 1) You can add 3 1/4 cups hot water and 1/4 cup thick coconut milk.\n 2) Toasted cashew nuts can also be added for a richer flavor.\n 3) You can omit whole spices like cardamom, cloves, cinnamon and add a large pinch of garam masala powder at the time for sauteing the vegetables.\n 4) If you do not have coconut on hand, omit it and follow rest of recipe. Add 2 tbsp of milk to the ground paste in place of fresh coconut.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="13" recipeName="Soft Idli" serves="18-20 medium sized idlis or 9-10 medium sized idlis" ingredients="1 cup basmati rice or sona masoori rice or regular rice\n 1 cup parboiled rice\n ½ cup urad dal/black gram, skinned whole or skinned spilt\n ¼ cup poha/flattened rice\n ¼ tsp methi seeds/fenugreek seeds\n Water as required\n Salt\n Oil to apply to the idli moulds\n" method="1) Pick and wash both the rice and urad dal.\n 2) Soak the rice and poha in water for 4-5 hours.\n 3) Soak the urad dal with methi seeds separately for 4-5 hours.\n 4) Drain the soaked urad dal. reserve the water.\n 5) Grind the urad dal, methi seed with some of the reserved water till you get a smooth and fluffy batter.\n 6) Grind the rice to make a smooth batter.\n 7) Mix both the batters together in a large bowl or pan. add salt and mix well.\n 8) Cover and let the batter ferment for 8-9 hours.\n 9) After the fermentation process is over, the batter will become double in size and rise.\n 10)Gently mix the batter.\n 12)Grease the idli moulds.\n 13)Pour the batter in the moulds steam the idlis in a pressure cooker or steamer.\n 14)If using pressure cooker remove the vent weight.whistle.\n 15)Steam for 10-12 mins or until the idlis are done.\n 16)Remaining batter can be stored in the refrigerator.\n 17)Serve the steaming hot idlis with coconut chutney and sambar.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="14" recipeName="Tomato Omlete" serves="3-4" ingredients="1 cup gram flour/besan\n 2 medium size tomato, finely chopped\n 1 medium size onion, finely chopped\n ½ inch ginger, finely chopped\n 1 green chili, finely chopped\n ¼ or ½ cup coriander/cilantro leaves, chopped\n ¼ tsp red chilli powder\n a pinch of asafoetida (optional)\n a pinch of garam masala\n ¼ tsp turmeric powder (optional)\n 1.5 to 2 cups water\n Salt as required\n Sunflower oil as required for cooking the omelette\n" method="1) Mix all the ingredients together, except oil.\n 2) Make a medium consistency batter.\n 3) Heat a tava or a flat pan.\n 4) Smear some oil, about 1 tsp on the pan.\n 5) With a large spoon pour the batter on the pan.\n 6) Spread it lightly with the back of the spoon.\n 7) The technique is like the way we make pancakes.\n 8) You can even rotate and tilt the pan.\n 9) Add some oil drops on the edges and top of the omelette.\n 10)Flip and cook the other side.\n 11)Cook the tomato omelette till both sides are cooked.\n 12)Serve tomato omelette with brown bread or buns and some coriander chutney or tomato sauce.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="15" recipeName="Uttappam" serves="3-4" ingredients="2 cups (360 gm) parboiled rice\n 1/2 cup (90 gm) split and husked Bengal Gram (dhuli urad)\n 1/2 tsp fenugreek seeds\n 2 tsp salt \n An iron griddle or tawa \n Oil to smear the pan for cooking the uttapam\n " method="1) Soak rice, daal and methi in water for 5-6 hours.\n  2) Grind fine, add salt and enough water to make a dropping consistency and leave to ferment 5-6 hours. \n 3) Heat tawa, and brush oil over it. When really hot, splash a little water over it, and pour about 1 cup of batter on to it. \n 4) It will spread a little. When the edges start browning a bit, pour a trail of oil around it. \n 5) Turn it over and let it brown on the other side too. \n\n  FOR AN ONION UTTAPAM: \n Before you turn the uttapam over, sprinkle a mixture of finely chopped onions, tomatoes, coriander leaves and green chillies.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="16" recipeName="Veg Grilled Sandwitch" serves="2-3" ingredients="FOR THE GRILL VEG SANDWICH:\n 8-10 slices of white or brown bread or whole wheat bread or sandwich bread\n 1 medium potato, boiled and sliced into rounds\n 1 small to medium cucumber thinly sliced\n 1 small onion thinly sliced\n 1 small to medium tomato, thinly sliced\n Butter as required\n Chaat masala powder as required\n Roasted cumin powder as required\n Black salt or regular salt as required\n Freshly milled black pepper – optional\n Tomato ketchup or sauce to be served with the sandwiches\n\n  FOR THE CORIANDER/CILANTRO CHUTNEY:\n 1 cup chopped fresh coriander leaves/cilantro\n 1-2 garlic cloves, chopped\n 1 green chili, chopped\n ½ to ¾ tsp lemon juice or as required\n ½ tsp cumin powder\n Black salt or rock salt or sea salt as required\n" method="1) Making the coriander/cilantro chutney\n 2) In a grinder or blender grind all the above chutney ingredients to a smooth paste using very little water. keep the chutney aside. if there are leftovers, then keep in an airtight container in the refrigerator.\n 3) Preparing the grill veg sandwich:\n 4) Boil the potatoes. they should not be cooked too much or fall apart. just cooked well till soft. peel and slice them.\n 5) Rinse, peel and slice the onion, tomatoes and cucumber in thin rounds.\n 6) Butter all the bread slices. the butter has to be spread evenly and generously so that the bread does not become soggy on spreading the chutney. spread some green chutney on the slices.\n 7) Place a few slices of potatoes and then sprinkle with roasted cumin powder and chaat masala powder.\n 8) Then place 2 to 3 cucumber, tomato and onion slices. sprinkle roasted cumin powder, chaat masala powder and black salt.\n 9) Cover the sandwiches with the remaining slices of bread.\n 10)Spread butter on the top of slices.\n 11)In a pre heated grill, place the sandwich carefully with the buttered side facing at the bottom. be careful when doing this. now spread butter on the top side facing you.\n 12)Close the grill and grill the sandwiches for 2-3 minutes or till crisp and golden.\n 13)Remove the grilled sandwiches with a wooden spatula. in batches grill the next lot.\n 14)Serve the vegetable grill sandwich hot with tomato ketchup and coriander/cilantro chutney or any other green chutney of your choice\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="1s" recipeName="Baby Corn Manchurian" serves="4-5 persons" ingredients="15-16 baby corn, each cut diagonally into two\n 1 1/2 tbsps maida/all-purpose flour\n 1 tbsp cornflour\n 1 tsp rice flour (optional)\n 1 tsp ginger-garlic-green chilli paste\n Few tbsps water\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR SAUCE:\n 1/4 cup spring onions, finely chopped,\n 1 capsicum, finely sliced\n 1/2 tbsp finely minced garlic\n 1/2 tsp finely minced ginger\n 1-2 finely chopped green chillis\n 1/2 tsp red chilli pwd (preferably Kashmiri)\n 1 tsp soya sauce\n 1 tsp chilli sauce\n 1 1/2 tsps vinegar\n 2 tbsps tomato sauce\n 1/2 tsp brown sugar (optional)\n salt as required\n 1 1/2 tbsps sesame oil\n 1 tbsp finely chopped coriander leaves\n" method="1) Heat oil for deep frying in a heavy bottomed vessel.\n 2) In a bowl, combine maida, cornflour, rice flour, salt, ginger-garlic-green chilli paste and water to make a thick paste. Dip the washed and drained baby corns into the batter such that its well coated. Place each piece that is well coated with the batter into the hot oil. Reduce flame and deep fry till the baby corn is almost cooked. Increase the flame towards the end of the cooking process and fry the baby corn till it turns golden brown. Remove onto absorbent paper and keep aside.\n 3) Heat oil in a large wok and once the oil is piping hot, add the chopped garlic and stir fry for a few seconds. Add the green chillis and ginger and stir fry on high for a few seconds.\n 4) Add the whites of spring onions and stir fry on high for 3-4 mts, constantly tossing them. Add the sliced capsicum and stir fry for another 3 mts. They should retain their crunch.\n 5) Reduce to medium heat and add the brown sugar, soya sauce, tomato ketchup, chilli sauce and vinegar. Combine well and cook for 2 mts. Add 3 tbsps of water and cook for 2 mts.\n 6) Add the deep fried baby corn and combine. Toss on high flame for 1-2 mts. Turn off heat. Garnish with the chopped spring onion greens and coriander leaves.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="2s" recipeName="Chilli Paneer" serves="4" ingredients="3/4 cup paneer (cottage cheese) , cut into 12 mm. ( 1/2) thick strips\n oil for deep-frying\n\n  FOR THE BATTER:\n 1/4 cup cornflour\n 1/4 cup plain flour (maida)\n 1 tsp soy sauce\n Pinch of baking powder\n Salt to taste\n\n  OTHER INGREDIENTS:\n 1 tsp grated ginger (adrak)\n 2 tsp garlic (lehsun) , chopped\n 2 tsp chopped celery\n 1/4 cup chopped spring onions\n 2 to 3 green chillies , cut into 25 mm. (1) pieces\n 1/4 cup capsicum , sliced\n 1 tsp soy sauce\n 1 tsp sugar\n 1 tbsp cornflour mixed with 3 tablespoons water\n 1 tsp oil\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR THE GARNISH:\n 1/2 cup spring onion greens , chopped\n" method="1) Combine all the ingredients for the batter in a bowl and make a smooth batter by adding approximately ¼ cup of water.\n 2) Coat the paneer pieces with the batter and deep fry in hot oil over a high flame till the paneer is golden brown.\n 3) Drain on absorbent paper and keep aside.\n\n  HOW TO PROCEED:\n 1) Heat the oil and add the ginger, garlic, celery, spring onion whites and green chillies and sauté over a high flame for 1 to 2 minutes.\n 2) Add the capsicum and sauté for a few more seconds.\n 3) Add the soya sauce, sugar, cornflour paste and salt and allow it to come to a boil.\n 4) Toss in the fried paneer and mix well.\n 5) Serve immediately, garnished with the spring onion greens.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="3s" recipeName="Chinese Bhel" serves="4" ingredients="2 tbsp oil\n 1/2 cup finely chopped spring onions\n 1/2 cup shredded cabbage\n 1/2 cup thinly sliced capsicum\n 1/2 cup shredded carrots\n 4 tsp schezuan sauce\n 2 tsp chilli oil\n 4 tsp ginger (adrak) water\n 2 tsp soy sauce to taste\n Salt to taste\n 4 cups crispy fried noodles\n" method="1) Heat the oil in a wok or kadhai on a high flame till the oil smokes.\n 2) Add the spring onions, cabbage, capsicum and carrots and sauté on a high flame for 2 minutes.\n 3) Add the schezuan sauce, chilli oil, ginger water and soya sauce and salt and sauté on a high flame for another minute.\n 4) Remove from the flame and transfer it to a bowl.\n 5) Add the fried noodles and toss well. Serve immediately.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="4s" recipeName="Idli Manchurian" serves="4-5 persons" ingredients="6-8 left over idlis, cut each into 8-9 pieces\n 2 tbsps maida/all-purpose flour\n 1 tbsp cornflour\n 1 tsp ginger-garlic-green chilli paste\n A little less than 1/2 cup warm water\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR SAUCE:\n 1/4 cup spring onions, finely chopped\n 1/2 capsicum, finely sliced\n 1 tbsp finely minced garlic\n 1/4 tsp finely minced ginger\n 1-2 finely chopped green chillis\n 1/4 tsp red chilli pwd (preferably Kashmiri)\n 1/2 tsp soya sauce\n 1/4 tbsp chilli sauce\n 1 tsp vinegar\n 1 1/2 tbsps tomato sauce\n 1/2 tsp brown sugar (optional)\n Salt as required\n 1 1/2 tbsps sesame oil\n 1 tbsp finely chopped coriander leaves OR finely chopped spring onion greens\n" method="1) Heat oil for deep frying in a heavy bottomed vessel. 2) In a bowl, combine maida, cornflour, salt, ginger-garlic-green chilli paste and water to make a thick paste. Dip the idli pieces into the batter such that its well coated. Place each piece that is well coated with the batter into the hot oil. Do not crowd the vessel. Reduce flame and deep fry till it turns lightly brown. Increase the flame towards the end of the cooking process and fry till it turns golden brown. Remove onto absorbent paper and keep aside. 3) Heat oil in a large wok and once the oil is piping hot, add the chopped garlic and stir fry for a few seconds. Add the green chillis and ginger and stir fry on high for a few seconds. 4) Add the whites of spring onions and stir fry on high for 3-4 mts, constantly tossing them. Add the sliced capsicum and stir fry for another 3 mts. They should retain their crunch. 5) Reduce to medium heat and add the brown sugar, soya sauce, tomato ketchup, chilli sauce and vinegar. Combine well and cook for 2 mts. Add 4-5 tbsps of water and cook for 2 mts. 6) Add the deep fried idli pieces and combine. Toss on high flame for 1-2 mts. Turn off heat. Garnish with the chopped spring onion greens or coriander leaves." />
    <RecipeDetails id="5s" recipeName="Manchow Soup" serves="4" ingredients="4 1/2 cups Clear Vegetable Stock (Chinese) or water with 1 vegetarian seasoning cube\n 2 tbsp finely chopped tomatoes\n 2 tbsp finely chopped capsicum\n 2 tbsp finely chopped cauliflower\n 2 tbsp finely chopped carrots\n 2 tbsp finely chopped cabbage\n 2 tbsp finely chopped garlic\n 2 tbsp chopped ginger\n 1 tbsp fresh finely chopped mint leaves (phudina)\n 1 tbsp chopped coriander (dhania)\n 3 tsp soy sauce\n 2 pcs cornflour dissolved in ½ cup water\n 1 tbsp oil\n Salt and black pepper (kalimirch) powder to taste\n" method="1) Heat the oil in a wok or kadai over a high flame. Add the garlic, ginger, vegetables and stir-fry for 2 to 3 minutes over a high flame.\n 2) Add the stock, mint, coriander, soya sauce, salt and pepper.\n 3) Add the cornflour paste to the soup and boil for 1 minute. Serve hot.\n\n  TIPS:\n 1) To make a clear vegetable stock quickly, just add roughly cut carrots, onion and celery to a vesseful of water and boil for about 15 minutes.\n 2) Strain and use the liquid as required.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="6s" recipeName="Masala Papad" serves="2" ingredients="2 plain papad, (available in Indian grocery stores)\n 2 medium tomatoes, seeded and diced very small to make a approx. 1cup\n 1/2 English or deseeded cucumber, cut in very small pieces to make it about ½  cup\n 2 tablespoons cilantro finely chopped\n 1 teaspoon ginger finely shredded, optional\n 1 green chili finely chopped, optional\n ½ lemon\n 2 teaspoon oil\n\n  SPICE MIX FOR GARNISHING:\n 1/2 teaspoon salt\n 1/4 teaspoon black salt\n 1/2 teaspoon dry roasted cumin seeds powder\n 1/8 teaspoon black pepper\n Pinch red chili\n" method="1) Mix all the dry ingredients to make a spice mix, set aside.\n 2) Mix tomatoes, cucumbers, cilantro, ginger, and green chili, set aside\n 3) Lightly oil the papads from both sides, set aside.\n 4) Preheat the skillet over medium high heat. Roast the papads on both sides in the skillet one at a time, pressing with spatula. The papads will change to a light yellow with a few brown spots. Be careful not to over-roast. Fold the Papads in quarters while they are hot, making triangles right on the skillet.\n 5) Remove the papads from the skillet and break on the folds, creating four triangles from each one.\n 6) Take one piece of papad and top it with cucumber, tomato, ginger, green chili, and cilantro. Drizzle with lemon juice and sprinkle the spice mix on top.\n\n  NOTES:\n 1) Removing the seeds from the tomatoes keeps the papads crunchy.\n 2) English cucumber is crisper on the outside and tender on the inside.\n 3) You can prepare  the masala papad in advance, and add the toppings just before serving.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="7s" recipeName="Paneer Tikka" serves="Makes 3 paneer tikka skewers" ingredients="Onion - 1 cubed\n Capsicum - 1 cubed\n Tomato - 1 chopped into squares\n\n  FOR THE MARINATION:\n Paneer -15 medium cubes\n Hung Curd - 3 tbsp\n Chilli powder - 1 tsp\n Turmeric powder - a pinch\n Garam masala powder - 1/2 tsp\n Tandoori masala / Chat Masala powder - 1/2 tsp (optional)\n Lemon juice - 1 tsp\n Pepper powder\n Ginger garlic paste - 1/2 tbsp\n Oil - 1 tbsp\n\n  HOW TO MAKE HUNG CURD:\n Hang 1/4 cup curd in a muslin cloth)or any thin cloth) for an hour to make the required hung curd.\n" method="1) Chop capsicum, tomato and onion into medium sized squares just enough to insert into skewers. Cube the paneer and make it ready. Now mix the ingredients listed under 'for the marination' and keep aside.\n 2) Now mix paneer with the marinated ingredients and keep refrigerated for an hr. Then take it out and insert the paneer,capsicum, tomato and onion in skewers alternatively. Arrange the remaining paneer pieces on the tray itself. Brush with oil on top.\n 3) Preheat the oven at 210 deg C and arrange the paneer tikkas in the baking tray and grill the paneer tikkas for 15-18mins turning over the skewers in between for even cooking. Your paneer tikkas are ready, serve hot with green chutney and raw onions.\n\n  NOTES: 1) You can even marinate capsicum,onion and tomato with the marination ingredients or just insert them raw. I usually do the paneer marination first then use the left over marination curd mix for onion-tomato-capsicum.\n 2) You can also arrange the paneer tikkas straight on the wire rack itself but be careful with the temperature (if you are using this method) as the tikkas are exposed to the flame directly.\n 3) You can skip tomatoes and use different color capsicums too.\n My oven has maximum temperature of 250 deg C but I was adviced by the demo person not to use the maximum temperature even if the recipe calls for it. So I lowered the temperature and grilled for an extra 5mins, the outcome was good. In microwave, you can grill it for 13-15 mins.\n Make sure the paneer pieces are firm enough to insert else it will break in between. I used Hatsun paneer which works best, milky mist is good too." />
    <RecipeDetails id="8s" recipeName="Sweet Corn Soup" serves="3" ingredients="Sweet Corn kernels - 1/2 cup\n Carrot - 1 finely chopped\n Beans - 3 chopped finely\n Water - 2 cups\n Pepper Powder - 1/8 tsp\n Cornflour - 2 tsp\n Onion - 1 tbsp finely chopped (optional)\n Spring Onion - 2 tbsp\n Black / White Pepper powder - 1/2 tsp\n Sugar - 1/2 tsp\n Oregano -1/4 tsp\n Salt - to taste\n" method="1) Make all your vegetables ready by chopping it finely. First saute carrot,beans and onion in 1 tsp of oil till raw smell leaves. Boil water in a container when it starts boiling add all the vegetables (except spring onion).\n 2) Allow the vegetables to get cooked....wait till they turn soft yet crunchy enough to bite.Meanwhile mix 1.5 tsp cornflour in 2 tbsp water without any lumps and keep it ready.\n 3) Once the water is reduced a little and veggies have turned soft, add the cornflour mixture stir once. The soup will start to thicken slowly after cornflour mixture is added...At this stage add sugar,pepper powder and give a quick stir.Let it simmer for 3mins.\n 4) Then add oregano mix well.Finally garnish with spring onions and switch off.\n 5) While serving garnish with more spring onion, sprinkle pepper powder and serve hot!\n\n  NOTES:\n 1) If you get white pepper then use it which tastes best.\n 2) Adjust cornflour according to the desired thickness consistency you want your soup to be.\n 3) You can also add cream style corn along with the vegetables for extra flavour.I had no luck getting it so made my soup with easily available ingredient in my pantry.\n 4) You can also add cabbage instead of onion.Add it along with carrot and beans wile sauteing. Sauteing the veggies before is purely optional but it will avoid the raw smell of the veggies so I always do it.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="9s" recipeName="Tomato Soup" serves="3" ingredients="6  medium tomatoes, cut in small pieces to make about 4 cups of chopped tomatoes\n 1 medium carrot, peeled and cut in small pieces to make about 1/3 cup of chopped carrots\n 1 celery stick, cut into small pieces to make about 1/3 cup of chopped celery\n 1/2” ginger peeled and sliced\n 1 teaspoons of oil\n 1/2 teaspoon salt, adjust to taste\n 1/2 teaspoon sugar, adjust to taste\n 1/8 teaspoon black pepper\n\n  SEASONING:\n 2 teaspoons oil\n 1/2 teaspoon cumin seed (jeera)\n Pinch of asafetida\n 1 tablespoon cilantro finely chopped (hara dhania)\n" method="1) Heat the oil in a saucepan over medium heat. Lightly brown the ginger. Add carrots and celery. Stir fry two minutes.\n 2) Add the tomatoes, salt, sugar, and pepper. Cook until tomatoes are mushy.\n 3) Let the tomatoes cool, then pure in blender.\n 4) Heat the oil in a saucepan. Add the cumin seed and asafetida. As the cumin seeds crack, add cilantro and stir for a minute.\n 5) Add the tomato pure and approx. 1¼ cup of water (adjust the water to your taste).\n 6) When the soup boils, turn the heat to low and let it simmer three to four minutes.\n 7) Serve hot, I like to serve with few pieces of  croutons.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="10s" recipeName="Vegetable Soup" serves="4" ingredients="2 tablespoons oil\n 1/2 teaspoon cumin seed (jeera)\n 1 bay leaf (tajpat)\n 6 cloves (long)\n 1 teaspoon salt\n 1/2 cup carrots, peeled and chopped into rounds\n 1 small potato peeled and diced\n 1/4 cup fresh green beans cut into 3/4-inch parts\n 1/4 cup celery chopped\n 1 cup cabbage chopped\n 1-1/2 cup tomato chopped\n 1/4 cup corn kernels\n 3 cups of water\n 1/4 teaspoon ground black pepper\n 1 to 2 teaspoons freshly squeezed lemon juice\n" method="1) Heat the oil in a saucepan over medium high heat, Test the heat by adding one  cumin seed to the oil; if the seed cracks right away, the oil is ready.\n 2) Add the cumin seeds. As they crack, add carrots, potatoes, green beans, bay leaf, cloves, and salt. Cook two to three minutes, stirring occasionally.\n 3) Add corn, cabbage, celery, tomato, and three cups of water. When it boils, turn the heat down to low medium.\n 4) Cover and cook 25 to 30 minutes, until the vegetables are tender.\n 5) Add the black pepper and lemon juice. Taste and season with additional salt and pepper as needed.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="11s" recipeName="Vegetable Manchurian Dry" serves="4-5 persons" ingredients="2 cups finely chopped capsicum, cabbage, carrot, beans and spring onion whites (packed cups)\n 2 tbsps maida/all-purpose flour\n 2 tbsps cornflour\n 1/2 tbsp rice flour\n 1 tbsp ginger-garlic-green chilli paste\n 1/4 tsp soy sauce\n 1/2 tsp black pepper powder\n Warm water as required (less than 1/2 cup is needed)\n Salt to taste\n Oil for deep frying\n\n  FOR SAUCE:\n 1/4 cup spring onions, finely chopped\n 1 1/2 tbsps finely minced garlic\n 1/2 tbsp finely minced ginger\n 2 finely chopped green chillis\n 1/2 tsp red chilli powder (preferably Kashmiri)\n 2 tsps soya sauce\n 1/2 tbsp chilli sauce\n 2 tsps vinegar\n 2 tbsps tomato sauce\n 1 tsp brown sugar\n Salt as required\n 1 tbsp sesame oil\n 1/2 – 2 tbsps finely chopped coriander leaves OR spring onion greens\n" method="1) Heat oil for deep frying in a heavy bottomed vessel.\n 2) In a bowl, combine maida, cornflour, rice flour, salt, ginger-garlic-green chilli paste, pepper pwd, soy sauce, salt and all the finely chopped vegetables. Sprinkle little water to make a thick mixture. Add water little by little and use only as much water as required to form small balls. You should be able to make small balls as shown in the picture above.\n 3) Carefully place each ball into the hot oil. Do not crowd the vessel. Reduce flame and deep fry the vegetable balls till cooked. Increase the flame towards the end of the cooking process and fry till they turn golden brown. Remove onto absorbent paper and keep aside.\n 4) Heat oil in a large wok and once the oil is piping hot, add the chopped garlic and stir fry for a few seconds. Add the green chillis and ginger and stir fry on high for a few seconds.\n 5) Add the whites of spring onions and stir fry on high for 2 mts, constantly tossing them.\n 6) Add the vegetable balls and stir fry for another 3 mts. They should retain their crunch. Reduce to medium heat and add the brown sugar, soya sauce, tomato ketchup, chilli sauce and vinegar. Mix well and cook for 2 mts. Add 3-4 tbsps of water and cook for 2 mts.\n 7) Toss on high flame for 1-2 mts. Turn off heat. Garnish with the chopped spring onion greens and/or coriander leaves.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="1sn" recipeName="Aloo Vada(Bhonda)" serves="3" ingredients="3 medium potatoes boiled peeled and roughly chopped (this will make 2 cups of chopped potatoes)\n 1 tablespoon oil\n 1/2 teaspoon black mustard seeds (rai)\n 7-10 curry leaves chopped, optional\n 1/4 teaspoon turmeric (haldi)\n 1 tablespoon finely chopped ginger\n 1 green chili finely chopped adjust to taste\n 2 tablespoons chopped cilantro (hara dhania)\n 1/2 teaspoon salt adjust to taste\n\n  FOR BATTER:\n 1/2 cup besan, gram flour (available in Indian grocery stores)\n 1 tablespoon rice flour\n 1/8 teaspoon asafetida (hing)\n 1/4 teaspoon baking soda\n 1/4 teaspoon red pepper\n 1/2 teaspoon salt adjust to taste\n About 1/4 cup of water\n Oil to fry\n" method="BATTER:\n In a bowl mix besan, rice flour, salt, asafetida, pepper, and baking powder. Add water slowly to make a thick and smooth batter. Set aside.\n\n  VADA:\n 1) Heat oil in a frying pan on medium heat moderately.\n 2) Add mustard seeds as the seeds crack add curry leaves, (curry leaves splatters) potatoes, ginger, green chili, turmeric, and salt.\n 3) Stir fry for about 3 minutes over medium heat. Add cilantro mix it well. Turn of the heat.\n 4) Let the potato mix cool off, divide them into about 12 pieces and make them into smooth round ball, they will be little smaller then golf ball.\n 5) Heat about 1”of oil in a frying pan on medium high heat. To check if the oil is ready, put one drop of batter in oil. The batter should come up but not change color right away.\n 6) Dip the potato balls into the batter one at a time, making sure the potato balls are completely covered with batter. Then, slowly drop them into the frying pan.\n 7) Turn them occasionally. Fry the batata vadas until all sides are golden-brown.\n 8) Batata vadas will take about four minutes to cook.\n 9) Serve them hot with cilantro chutney.\n\n  VARIATIONS:\n Serve them with sandwich buns using cilantro chutney as spread. Now this is known as Vada pav.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="2sn" recipeName="Bhel Puri Chat" serves="4-6" ingredients="3 cups puffed rice (murmura, kurmura) available in Indian grocery stores.\n 1 cup fine sav (vermicelli-like snack made from gram flour) available in Indian grocery stores.\n 1 cup papdi broken in small pieces (recipe you can find on my web site) or available in Indian grocery stores.\n 1/2 cup of chopped boiled potatoes\n 1/2 cup of chopped cucumber\n 1/2 cup of chopped tomatoes remove the seeds\n 2 tablespoons chopped cilantro\n 1/2 teaspoon salt (adjust to taste)\n 4 tablespoon of hari cilantro chutney\n 4 tablespoon of tamarind chutney\n 1 tablespoon minced green pepper optional\n\n  FOR GARNISH:\n 1/4 cup fine sav\n 2 tablespoons lemon juice\n" method="1) In frying pan over medium heat dry roast the puffed rice for 3 to 4 minutes. Let it cool.\n 2) Combine the dry ingredients (puffed rice, sev, papdi,and salt) together and mix well. Set aside until ready to serve\n 3) Mix chopped potatoes, cucumber, tomatoes, cilantro,and minced green pepper if you like it hot, and set aside.\n 4) When ready to serve, combine the dry ingredients and potato mixture.\n 5) Add hari cilantro and tamarind chutneys to your taste, making sure the chutneys coat the bhel puri. Garnish with sev and drizzle with lemon juice to taste.\n\n  NOTES: \n Assemble bhel puri just before serving to prevent the puffed rice and sev from getting soggy\n\n  TIPS:\n Puffed rice (murmura) loses some of its crispness with time. Roasting restores the crispness and freshness.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="3sn" recipeName="Corn Fingers" serves="5" ingredients="1 cup grated corn\n 1 cup milk\n ½ tsp pepper pwd\n 2 tbsp grated cheese\n 3/4 to 1 cup left over cooked rice\n 1 tbsp chopped coriander leaves\n 1 tbsp chopped green chillis\n 2 tbsp maida\n 1 tbsp cornflour\n ½ cup water\n ½ cup bread crumbs\n 1 tsp cumin seeds\n 1 tbsp butter\n Salt\n" method="1) Heat butter in a dish and add the cumin seeds and let them splutter.Add the corn, salt and pepper pwd along with milk and let the corn cook in this milk till the milk is absorbed. Add the cooked rice and cover with lid for 5 mts.\n 2) Coarsely mash the corn and rice mixture with the back of a ladle. Remove from heat.\n 3) Add grated cheese, coriander leaves and green chillis and mix well.\n 4) Shape as longitudinal thick fingers as shown below in the picture.\n\n  CORN FINGERS BEFORE DEEP FRYING:\n 1) This recipe makes 10-12 fingers. Refrigerate for 20 mts.\n 2) Meanwhile add water to the maida and cornflour to make a flowing batter.\n 3) Heat enough oil in a vessel for deep frying the corn fingers.\n 4) Dip each corn finger in the maida-cornflour batter and then roll in bread crumbs and deep fry to a golden brown shade.\n 5) Serve with tomato sauce or mint chutney.\n\n  TIPS:\n Use left over cooked rice as a binding ingredient instead of potato\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="4sn" recipeName="Corn Vada" serves="4" ingredients="Indian corn kernels - 1 cup+1/4 cup\n Chana dal - 1/2 cup, soak in 1 cup water for an hour\n Onion - 1, medium, finely chopped\n Green chillis - 2,\n Ginger - 1/2\n Cumin seeds - 1/2 tsp (optional)\n Coriander leaves - 2 tbsps, finely chopped\n Salt to taste\n Oil for deep frying\n" method="1) Grind the corn kernels (1 cup) and the soaked and drained chana dal, green chilies and ginger to a coarse paste adding about 1-2 tbsps of water.\n 2) Remove to a bowl. Add 1/4 cup of boiled sweet corn, chopped onions, coriander leaves, cumin seeds and salt and mix well.\n 3) Form lemon sized balls with the mixture. Flatten it on your palm to make a patti shape. Prepare patties with the rest of the mixture. Keep in fridge for 10 mts.\n 4) Heat oil for deep frying. Once its hot, reduce flame to medium and slolwy place the patties in the oil and fry them on both sides to a golden brown color.\n 5) Serve warm with tomato sauce or any chutney of your choice.\n\n  TIPS:\n 1) You can add a tbsp of corn flour to the ground mixture.\n 2) You can add fennel seeds instead of cumin seeds.\n 3) Pudina aka mint leaves also add great flavor to the vada. Add 5-6 leaves.\n 4) Do not use the tender variety of Indian corn. Use the slightly mature corn cobs. Peel the corn kernels and do not boil them.\n 5) While grinding, do not make a smooth paste but it should be slightly coarse.\n 6)If you do not have maize aka Indian corn on hand, use American sweet corn kernels.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="5sn" recipeName="Dabeli Spicy Potato Sandwich" serves="4" ingredients="SPICE MIX:\n 1 red chili dry\n 1 teaspoon coriander (dhania) seeds\n 2 cloves (laung / lavang)\n 1/2 inch cinnamon (dalchini)\n 1/2 teaspoon cumin (jeera) seeds\n 4 black pepper\n\n  FILLING:\n 1 cup potato boiled and mashed (aloo)\n 2 tablespoons oil\n 1/2 teaspoon cumin (jeera) seeds\n 1/2 teaspoon salt\n Spice mix which we prepared that should be about 1 tablespoon\n 1 tablespoon tamarind paste (imli)\n 3 teaspoons sugar\n 1/2 cup water\n\n  ALSO NEED:\n 4 buns\n 2 tablespoons butter for cooking\n\n  TO SERVE:\n 1/4 cup roasted and crushed peanuts\n 1/4 cup fine sev available in Indian grocery stores\n 1/4 cup pomegranate (anar) seeds, if not available red or green grapes cut into small pieces\n 3 tablespoons cilantro chutney (dhania chutney)\n" method="FOR DABELI MASALA: \n Roast all the ingredients red chili, coriander, cloves, cumin seeds, cinnamon and black pepper, in a small pan on the medium heat for two minutes, spices will become very aromatic. Grind the spices to fine powder. This should make about one tablespoon.\n\n  FOR FILLING: \n 1) Heat the oil in pan on medium heat moderately. Add cumin seeds when seeds crack add potatoes spice mix, salt and tamarind paste, mix it well.\n 2) Add about half cup of water mix it and bring to boil, cook on low heat for about two minutes. Mix should be consistency of thick paste. Set aside.\n\n   HOW TO PROCEED:\n 1) Slice the buns into halves and toast the buns over skillet on medium heat using little butter both sides.\n 2) Over one half of the bun put about ¼ cup of the filling, top it with chutney, pomegranate, peanuts and fine save, sandwich with the other half of the bun.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="6sn" recipeName="Dahi Vada" serves="20" ingredients="FOR PREPARING VADAS:\n Black gram lentil - 1 cup, urad dal without skin, washed, soaked for 3 hours\n Yellow moong dal - 2 tbsps, soak for 2 hours (optional)\n Ginger - 2? piece\n Green chilies - 2 to 3\n Salt to taste\n Oil for deep frying\n\n  TO PREPARE DAHI CHAAT:\n Fresh curd - 2 cups, thick yogurt (it should not be sour)\n Water - 1 1/2 to 2 cups\n Powdered sugar - 1 1/2 heaped tbsps\n Red chilli powder - 1 heaped tbsp, approx\n Roasted cumin powder - 1 heaped tbsp, apporx\n Chaat masala powder -1 heaped tbsp, approx\n Pomegranate seeds - 1/2 cup\n Green chutney - 3/4 cup, approx\n Sweet tamarind chutney - 3/4 cup, approx\n Sev for garnish\n Fresh coriander leaves for garnish\n" method="1) Grind the urad dal, moong dal, green chilies, ginger and salt together to a fine pase. Add very very little cold water while grinding. (approx 2-3 tbsps). Remove to a wide bowl. Using your hand or hand beater, beat the batter for a good 5 mts till it is airy and light.\n 2) Pre-heat oil in a deep frying vessel, slowly drop large lemon sized quantity of batter into the hot oil. Deep fry on medium heat for sometime and then fry on high heat till golden brown.\n 3) Remove these deep fried vadas into a bowl of luke warm water and place them in it for a mt. Remove and gently press between your palms so that excess water oozes out. Keep them aside.\n 4) Finish making vadas with the rest of the remaining batter and put them in water like you did for the earlier batch, remove excess water and keep aside.\n 5) Beat curd well till smooth and add the water as required, 1/4 tsp red chilli pwd and 1/4 tsp cumin pwd and salt to taste.\n 6) Place the vadas in a serving bowl and pour the chilled curd mixture evenly all over the vadas, covering them completely.\n 7) Chill the vadas for sometime before serving. At the time of serving, take 2-3 vadas and place them in a serving plate, pour 2 tbsps of green chutney followed by 2 tbsps of sweet imli chutney, sprinkle some chaat powder, roasted cumin powder and and garnish with sev, fresh coriander leaves and pomegranate seeds.\n\n  TIPS:\n You can sprinkle some black salt too over the dahi vada.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="7sn" recipeName="Mirchi Vada" serves="Makes 8" ingredients="8 green chillies (I use yellow chilli peppers)\n\n  FOR FILLING:\n 1 cup potatoes boiled peeled and mashed\n 1/2 teaspoon salt\n 1/4 teaspoon cumin seeds (jeera)\n 1 teaspoon coriander powder (dhania)\n 1/4 teaspoon mango powder (amchoor)\n 1 tablespoon chopped cilantro (hara dhania)\n 1/4 teaspoon chilli powder (lal mirch), (optional)\n\n  FOR BATTER:\n 1/2 cup Besan (gram flour), (available in Indian grocery stores)\n 1/4 teaspoon salt\n 1/4 teaspoon cumin seeds (jeera)\n 1/8 tablespoon baking powder\n 1 tablespoon cilantro chopped (hara dhania)\n Approx. ¼ cup water\n Also need oil to deep fry\n" method="1) Vertically slit the chili and remove the seeds,.but not the stems. Set aside.\n 2) Mix all the filling ingredients together and set aside.\n 3) To make the vada batter, mix all the dry ingredients together: Besan, cumin seeds, baking powder and salt. Add the water slowly to make thick smooth batter, the consistency of pancake batter.\n 4) Add cilantro and mix it well.\n 5) Stuff the chilies with potato mix.\n 6) Heat one inch of oil in a frying pan over medium heat. To test, put one drop of batter in the oil. The batter should form a small ball on the surface of the pan, but not change color right away.\n 7) Dip the filled chilies in the batter one at a time, making sure each is covered with batter all around. Drop slowly into the frying pan.\n 8) Fry the mirchi vada until all sides are golden brown, four to five minutes, turning occasionally. Take them out and place them on a paper towel.\n 9) Vadas are best served hot. Serve them  Tamarind Chutney.\n\n  TIPS:\n 1) You can prepare the Mirchi Vadas in advance, and heat them in a 300°F oven before serving.\n 2) The left over makes great sandwiches.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="8sn" recipeName="Moong Dal Vada" serves="Makes 24 vadas" ingredients="1 cup split wash moong dal \n 1 cup potatoes boiled peeled and shredded\n Approx. 2 tablespoon finely chopped cilantro (hara dhania)\n 1 green chili minced adjust to taste\n 1 tablespoon finely grated ginger\n 1 teaspoon cumin seeds (jeera)\n 1/8 teaspoon asafetida (hing)\n 1/8 teaspoon of baking soda\n 1 teaspoon salt adjust to taste\n Oil to fry\n" method="1) Wash and soak dal in about 3 cups of water for four hours or longer.\n 2) Grind dal coarsely using very little water.\n 3) Add all the ingredients to the dal batter, potatoes, cilantro, green chili, ginger, cumin seeds, asafetida and salt, beat the batter for 2-3 minutes this will make the batter light. Add the water if needed, batter should be soft. If batter is too thick Vadas will be hard.\n 4) Heat the oil in a frying pan on medium high heat.\n 5) The frying pan should have about 1 inch of oil. To check if the oil is ready, put one drop of batter in oil. The batter should sizzle and come up but not change color right away. If oil is very hot vadas will not cook through and will not be crispy.\n 6) Place about 1 tablespoon of batter into the oil. Fry the vada in small batches. Fry vadas until golden-brown all around.\n 7) Moong Dal Vada should be crispy from outside and should be soft inside.\n 8) Serve them with Hari Cilantro Chutney.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="9sn" recipeName="Murukku" serves="40" ingredients="Rice flour - 4 cups, home made\n Roasted chickpeas powder - 1 cup \n Cumin seeds - 1 tsp\n Red chili powder - 1 tsp\n Asafoetida - 1/2 tsp, optional\n Butter - 3 tbsps, melted\n Salt - 1 tsp\n Oil for deep frying\n" method="1) Heat 2 cups water and a tsp of salt in a stainless steel vessel. Bring to a boil and reduce flame. Slowly add the rice flour and mix to form a gooey paste. Place lid and keep aside to cool.\n 2) Once the rice flour paste cools, add roasted chickpeas powder, cumin seeds, red chili powder, asafoetida powder and melted butter. Mix well to make a smooth dough. If required add a little more rice flour to form a smooth dough. Alternately, if you feel that the dough needs some water to form a dough, sprinkle some warm water and mix to form a smooth dough. Ensure that the dough is not too soft or hard, It should be just right to come through the press to form murukkus.\n 3) Heat oil for deep frying in a heavy bottomed vessel. While the oil is heating prepare the murukkus for deep frying.\n 4) Place a single star shaped disc in the murukku press, grease the insides of the mold, fill the mold with some of the prepared dough and make concentric shaped murukkus on a wax paper/greased banana leaf or a greased plastic sheet. This helps to easily transfer them into the hot oil. Prepare 6 to 7 for each batch based on how large the vessel is for deep frying.\n 5) To test if the oil is hot enough for deep frying, drop a small ball of the dough into the oil. If it sinks to the bottom of the vessel with a sizzle and come right up. The temperature of the oil is right for deep frying.\n 6) Reduce flame to medium and place 5 to 6 of the prepared murukkus and deep fry to a golden brown shade. Do not deep fry on high flame.\n 7) Remove onto absorbent paper. Once cool, store in air tight container.\n\n  TIPS:\n 1) To prepare rice flour at home. Soak 3 to 4 cups rice in water for 4 hours. Drain water and wash thoroughly. Drain water completely and spread on a thin cloth or paper. Dry overnight indoors. Next day grind the dried rice to a fine powder. Sieve to make a fine powder. Store in an air tight container upto 2 months.\n 2) Ensure that the dough is not too soft or hard, It should be just right to come through the press to form murukkus.\n 3) Always keep the unused dough covered while the rest of the murukkus are cooking.\n 4) While one batch of murukku is frying, start pressing the concentric circles/murukkus for the next batch to be fried. Do not prepare all the murukkus at once as they will dry out.\n 5) Do not fret too much if the murukku breaks while pressing into concentric circles. With practice, you should be able to make perfectly shaped murukkus.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="10sn" recipeName="Peanut Chat" serves="4" ingredients="1/2 cup raw peanuts\n 1/2+1/2 teaspoon salt adjust to taste\n 1/8 teaspoon turmeric (haldi)\n 3/4 cup tomatoes seeded cut in small cubes\n 3/4 cup cucumber cut in small cubes\n 1 tablespoon ginger finally chopped\n 1 green chili finally chopped adjust to taste\n 1/2 teaspoon roasted cumin seed powder (bhuna jeera)\n 1/8 teaspoon red chili powder\n 1/8 teaspoon black pepper\n 1/4 teaspoon sugar\n 1/2 teaspoon mango powder (amchoor)\n 1 tablespoon lemon juice\n" method="1) In a sauce pan add peanuts with 2 cups of water turmeric and 1/2 teaspoon of salt. Cook over medium high heat for about 25 minutes until peanuts are soft.\n 2) Drain the water and let it cool to room temperature.\n 3) Mix ginger, chili, 1/2 teaspoon salt, cumin seed powder, red chili powder, black pepper, sugar, mango powder and lemon juice together.\n 4) Mix the peanuts with tomatoes and cucumbers, add the spice mix and toss.\n 5) Peanut Chaat is ready to serve.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="11sn" recipeName="Potato Paneer Tots" serves="Makes about 24" ingredients="2 medium russet potatoes\n 1 cup mashed paneer\n 1 teaspoon salt, adjust to taste\n 1 finely chopped jalapeno pepper (hari mirch)\n 1/4 teaspoon black pepper\n Oil to fry\n\n  FOR BATTER:\n 3 tablespoon all purpose flour (maida, plain flour)\n 5 tablespoons water\n" method="1) Mix flour and water together and make a thin, smooth batter and keep aside.\n 2) Peel the skin off the potatoes and shred them in a grater or food processor.\n 3) In a pan boil the water. After it comes to boil put the shredded potatoes in the water and let it boil for two to three minutes until they are just tender. Note: don’t over cook the potatoes they will become mushy, should be able to feel the shredded potatoes\n 4) Once cooked, drain the water and pour some cold water over the potatoes.\n 5) Gently squeeze the excess water out of the potatoes, again making sure to not make the shredded potatoes mushy.\n 6) Next mix shredded potatoes, mashed paneer, and jalapeno pepper, and salt together\n 7) Divide the potato mixture in about 24 equal parts and form them into bullet shape. Keep aside.\n 8) Heat the oil in a frying pan on medium high heat.\n 9) The frying pan should have at least 1 ½ inch of oil. To check if the oil is ready, put one small piece of mix in the oil, it should sizzle and come up right away.\n 10)Dip the potato balls in the batter one at a time and slowly drop into the frying pan.\n 11)Turn them occasionally. Fry tots until golden-brown all around.\n 12)Remove them with a slotted spoon and drain on a paper towel.\n 13)Serve them hot with your choice of tomato ketchup or coriander (hari) chutney or tamarind (imli) chutney. They also taste great as is.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="12sn" recipeName="Potato Skins" serves="4" ingredients="4 medium size red potatoes\n 3 cups water\n 1 tablespoon salt\n 2 tablespoons oil\n\n  FILLING:\n 1/2 cup chickpeas\n 1/2 teaspoon salt\n 1/4 teaspoon black salt\n 1/2 teaspoon roasted cumin\n 1/2 teaspoon mango powder\n 1/2 teaspoon garam masala\n 1/4 teaspoon black pepper\n 1 tablespoon finely shredded ginger\n 1 tablespoon finely chopped green chili adjust to taste\n 1 teaspoon lemon juice\n\n  FOR GARNISH:\n 2 tablespoons Hari Cilantro Chutney\n 2 tablespoons Tamarind Chutney\n" method="1) Wash the potatoes and slice them into halves.\n 2) Boil approximately 3 cups of water in a pan over medium high heat; add salt, oil and potatoes.\n 3) Cover and cook potatoes till they are tender, which will take approximately 20 minutes. Remove them from the water.\n 4) Once the potatoes are cool to touch, scoop out the insides from the center leaving ¼ inch thickness to outside of the potato. Red potato works best for this recipe because they hold their shape nicely.\n 5) Set potatoes aside.\n\n  FILLING:\n Soak chickpeas for at least 8 hours in 3 cups of water or more.\n Boil the chickpeas in 1 ½ cup of water in a pressure cooker over medium high heat. As the pressure cooker begins to steam, lower    the heat to medium and cook for 6 minutes.\n Add all the spices, mix well and cook for 3-4 minutes over low heat.\n Spicy chickpeas should be a thick gravy-like consistency, not dry. As chickpeas cool they will absorb the water. Set aside.\n\n  ASSEMBLING POTATO SKIN:\n Take each potato bowl and coat the inside with one teaspoon of Hari Cilantro Chutney.\n Place 2 tablespoons of spiced chickpeas into the chutney coated bowl. Drizzle the top with tamarind chutney.\n Serve warmed up or at room temperature.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="13sn" recipeName="Rava Dhokla" serves="5" ingredients="Semolina - 1 cup, sooji\n Curd - 1 1/2 cups, yogurt (preferably sour)\n Buttermilk - 1/2 cup\n Salt to taste\n Green chilies - 2\n Ginger - 1/2 piece\n Besan - 1 tbsp, chickpea powder\n Sugar - 1/2 tsp\n Lemon juice - 1/2 tbsp\n Oil - 1 tbsp\n Eno Salt - 1 tsp\n Red chili powder - 1/2 tsp\n Fresh coriander leaves - for garnish\n Grated coconut - for garnish (optional)\n\n  FOR TEMPERING/TADKA:\n Mustard seeds - 1 tsp\n Cumin seeds - 1/2 tsp\n Sesame seeds - 1 heaped tbsp\n Curry leaves - 1 sprig\n Oil - 1/2 tbsp\n" method="1) In a bowl, mix semolina and curd. Mix well such that there are no lumps. Place lid and keep aside for at least 2 hours. Its a good idea to soak overnight in the refrigerator.\n 2) Make a coarse paste of green chilies and ginger.\n 3) At the time of preparing dhokla, add besan, lemon juice, green chilies-ginger paste, oil, sugar and salt to the soaked sooji yogurt batter mixture and mix well. The consistency should be like a thick dosa batter. Add buttermilk as required to reach the dosa batter consistency.\n 4) Grease a stainless steel vessel or an aluminum round cake pan that will easily fit into your pressure cooker or steaming vessel.\n 5) If using a pressure cooker, add water to it and place it on low flame with out lid. If using a steamer, add water and allow to steam.\n 6) To the sooji curd batter, add eno salt and mix well using your hand. You will find that the batter becomes frothy. Immediately, pour the batter into the greased vessel, sprinkle red chili powder and place lid.\n 7) Place this vessel in the pressure cooker or steamer and steam it on high without weight for 16-18 mts. Turn off flame and allow to cool for 10 mts.\n 8) When the dhokla is cooling prepare the tempering. Heat oil in a small pan, add mustard seeds and allow to splutter. Next add cumin seeds, sesame seeds, curry leaves and saute for a few secs. Turn off flame and keep aside.\n 9) Remove dhokla vessel from the pressure cooker and use a knife to run along the edge of the dhokla to loosen it. Overturn the vessel on to a plate carefully and again turn it back to its original position with red chili powder on top. Pour the tempering on top of dhokla, sprinkle fresh corinader leaves and grated coconut. Cut into pieces and serve warm with green chutney made with coriander leaves, mint leaves, sugar, ginger and green chillies.\n\n  TIPS:\n 1) Alternately, you need not overturn the dhokla on to a plate. Pour the tempering all over the dhokla, cut into pieces and serve with green chutney.\n 2) To prepare dhania chutney or green chutney - Blend 1 cup packed chopped fresh coriander leaves, 1/2 cup mint leaves, 2 green chilis, 1/2 ginger piece, 1 tbsp lemon juice, 1/2 tsp sugar, salt to taste. You can add a clove of garlic if you like the flavor of garlic in your chutney.\n 3) Sometimes the steaming process takes longer than 18 mts. Do steam for additional 10 mts if necessary.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="14sn" recipeName="Vada Pav" serves="6-8" ingredients="2 large potatoes, lightly mashed\n 1/4 tsp cumin seeds\n 1/2 tsp mustard seeds\n Few curry leaves\n 1 onion, finely chopped\n 2 green chillis, finely chopped\n 1/2 tsp ginger garlic paste\n 1/4 tsp turmeric pwd\n 1 tbsp lemon juice\n Fresh coriander leaves for garnish\n Salt to taste\n 1/2 tbsp oil\n\n  FOR BATTER:\n 1 cup besan/chickpea flour/senaga pindi\n 2 tbsps rice flour\n Salt to taste\n 1/2 tsp red chilli pwd\n Pinch of cooking soda\n Water as required\n" method="1) Heat oil in a vessel, add the mustard seed and allow them to splutter. Add the cumin seeds and let them brown lightly. Add green chillis, curry leaves and ginger-garlic paste and saute for a mt. Immediately add the onions and saute for 3 mts.\n 2) Add the salt, turmeric pwd and combine. Add the mashed potatoes and combine and cook for a mt. Add coriander leaves and lemon juice and turn off heat. Cool and make small balls and keep aside.\n 3) Place a heavy bottomed vessel on the stove, add enough oil for deep-frying and allow it to heat on low flame. While the oil is heating prepare the batter.\n 4) In a bowl, add the ingredients required for making the batter. Slowly add water and make a slightly thick, flowing batter. Dip the potato ball in the batter and coat it well and place in the hot oil. Cook on medium high flame till golden brown. Remove onto absorbent paper.\n 5) Serve hot with chutney or tomato sauce and a cup of masala chai OR proceed to prepare Vada Pav.\n\n  HOW TO ASSEMBLE VADA PAV:\n Cut pav bread horizontally in the center. Spread a tsp of green chutney and garlic chutney (optional) on one of the halves of the pav, layer with onion slices, place a batata vada and cover with the other half of pav. Gently press using your palm and serve along with lemon wedges.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="15sn" recipeName="Mixed Vegetable Pakora" serves="5" ingredients="Carrots: 1 (large, peel and cut into thick julienne)\n French Beans: 8 (string and cut into 1 1/2 pieces)\n Potato: 1 (large, peel and cut into thick julienne)\n Cabbage: 1/4 head (cut into thick julienne)\n Chickpea flour: 1 1/2 cups (sengapindi/besan)\n Red chili powder: 3/4 tsp\n Ginger garlic paste: 1/4 tsp\n Carom seeds: 3/4 tsp (ajwain/vaamu)\n Hot oil: 2 tsps\n Salt: to taste\n Water: as required (approx 1/2 cup to 3/4 cup water)\n Oil: for deep frying\n" method="1) In a bowl, add the chickpea flour with salt, chili powder, ginger garlic paste, carom seeds and hot oil. Add the thick julienne mixed vegetables to this mixture and mix.\n 2) Add little water and mix well that it coats the vegetables. Do not add too much water.\n 3) Heat enough oil for deep frying in a heavy bottomed vessel. It should be piping hot. Do the sizzle test. (Drop a little chick pea batter into the hot oil, if it sizzles and comes to the surface of the vessel, then the oil is ready for deep frying).\n 4) Carefully drop the chickpea flour coated julienne vegetables into the hot oil. Do not overcrowd the vessel.\n 5) Reduce heat to medium and deep fry till they turn golden brown.\n 6) Use a ladle to turn them so that they cook all over.\n 7) Once they turn golden brown, remove on to absorbent paper. Serve as evening snack over a hot cup of masala chai.\n\n  TIPS:\n 1) Adjust the quantity of chickpea flour according to the vegetables.\n 2) Add few tbsps water at a time while making the batter. It should be like a paste that coats the vegetables and not like a runny mixture.\n 3) You can add a pinch of roasted cumin powder.\n 4) Use curry leaves if you do not have kasoori methi. If you do not have both curry leaves and kasoori methi, omit them and follow rest of the recipe.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="1n" recipeName="Bisibele Bath" serves="2-3" ingredients="1 cup rice\n 1/2 cup toor dal (split red gram)\n 1 1/2 tsp tamarind paste\n 1 cup onions, cut lengthwise and halved\n 1/4 cup green beans, cut into 1-inch pieces\n 1/4 cup carrots, cut into small cubes\n 5-6 cashew nuts, fried and cut into pieces (optional)\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR MASALA:\n 8-10 red chillies\n 1 1/2 tsp dhania (coriander seeds)\n 1/4 tsp methi (fenugreek seeds)\n 1 tsp urad dal ( black gram)\n 1 1/4 tsp chana dal (split bengal gram)\n 1-inch piece cinnamon\n 2 cloves\n 1 1/2 tsp grated dry coconut\n 7-8 tsp vegetable oil or ghee (clarified butter)\n Or you can use ready-made bisi bele bhath masala.\n\n  FOR SEASONING:\n 2 tsp vegetable oil\n 1 1/2 tsp mustard seeds (rai)\n Asafoetida powder (hing), a pinch\n 6-7 curry leaves\n" method="1) Heat oil in a pan and fry the cashew nuts and keep aside.\n 2) Saute the onions, beans, and carrots for a couple of minutes.\n 3) Roast the dhania, methi, chana, cloves and toor dal in 1/2 tsp oil, till light brown. Then add the red chillies and dry coconut, and fry for a minute.\n 4) Cool and powder these along with the cinnamon, and keep aside.\n 5) Coarsely grind the rice and toor dal (pulse it for 2 seconds). You can skip this step if you like.\n 6) Take a medium-sized container and add the rice and dal, and the vegetables. Add the tamarind paste and salt, and 4 cups of water.\n 7) Add the ground bisi bele bhath masala. Check the taste and adjust salt and tamarind acordingly.\n 8) Cook the rice, dal, and vegetables in a pressure cooker for about 5-7 whistles (until cooked).\n 9) Heat 2 tsp of oil in a small pan. Add the hing and mustard seeds. When the seeds start popping, add the curry leaves. Pour this seasoning over the cooked bisi bele bhath.\n 10)Stir in the cashew nuts, and mix well.\n 11)Serve hot with some ghee and pappadam.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="2n" recipeName="Cauliflower Peas Curry" serves="4" ingredients="4 cups cauliflower, separated into medium florets\n 1 cup peas, fresh or frozen (if using frozen, thaw for 10 minutes or rinse in warm water)\n 1/2 tsp red chilli powder\n 1 tsp curry powder (store-bought)\n 1 tsp amchur powder (dried mango powder)\n 2 tbsp cilantro (coriander leaves), finely chopped\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR SEASONING:\n 2 tbsp vegetable oil\n 1 tsp cumin seeds (jeera)\n 1-inch piece ginger, cut into strips (julienned)\n 4-5 green chillies, slit lengthwise\n 1/2 tsp turmeric powder\n" method="1) Heat the oil in a wide skillet. Add the cumin seeds and fry until golden. Add the green chillies and ginger and fry for a minute.\n 2) Add the turmeric powder and cauliflower and stir-fry for 2-3 minutes. Sprinkle some salt and water and cover and cook on medium-high heat, stirring occasionally, until the pieces brown.\n 3) Add the curry powder, red chilli powder, and amchur powder and saute for 2 minutes.\n 4) Add the peas and salt as needed and saute for a minute; then cover and cook until the cauliflower and peas are tender. Remove from heat.\n 5) Garnish the cauliflower-peas curry with cilantro and serve with plain rice or roti.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="3n" recipeName="Cucumber Curry" serves="1-2" ingredients="4 cups (2 medium) zucchini, peeled and sliced (not too thin)\n 1/4 tsp red chilli powder\n 1/2 tsp sugar\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR SEASONING:\n 4 tsp vegetable oil\n Asafoetida powder (hing), a pinch\n 1/2 tsp cumin seeds (jeera)\n 1/2 tsp coriander-cumin powder (dhania-jeera)\n 2 green chillies, slit lengthwise\n 1/4 tsp turmeric powder\n" method="1) Heat oil in a wide skillet. Add the asafoetida and cumin seeds and fry until golden. Add the turmeric powder, green chillies, coriander-cumin powder and saute for half a minute.\n 2) Add the zucchini slices along with salt. Stir-fry the zucchini curry for 3-4 minutes.\n 3) Add the red chilli powder and fry for a few seconds. Add 1/2 cup water and sugar and cover and cook on medium heat until the zucchini is tender.\n 4) Serve the zucchini curry hot with plain rice.\n\n  TIPS:\n If you want the gravy to be thick, rather than watery, add 1 tsp rice flour or chickpea flour (besan), and cook until it thickens a bit. Or add only 1/4 cup of water while cooking the zucchini, and cook uncovered towards the end to evaporate the water. \n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="4n" recipeName="Curd Rice" serves="6" ingredients="2 cups rice (jasmine or any other rice; sticky rice is fine,too)\n 2 cups plain yogurt, regular, nonfat, or lowfat\n 1 cup water\n 1/4 cup cucumber, finely chopped (or chopped onion, tomato, or grated carrot- optional)\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR SEASONING:\n 2 tsp vegetable oil\n 1/2 tsp chana dal (split bengal gram)\n 1/2 tsp urad dal (split black gram)\n 1/2 tsp mustard seeds (rai)\n 1/4 tsp cumin seeds (jeera)\n 1 green chilli, finely chopped\n 1 red chilli, cut into a couple pieces\n 1 tsp ginger, grated (optional)\n 5-6 curry leaves\n 1 tsp cilantro, finely chopped\n" method="1) Cook the rice in a rice cooker or pressure cooker with 4 cups of water. Let the rice cool.\n 2) Heat oil in a small pan and add the chana dal, urad dal, and fry for a few seconds.\n 3) Add mustard seeds, green chillies, red chilli, and ginger.\n 4) When the mustard seeds start to pop, add curry leaves. Let the seasoning cool.\n 5) Mix the rice with chopped cucumber, yogurt, water, and salt.\n 6) Add the seasoning to the yogurt rice. Mix well.\n 7) Garnish with cilantro, and serve.\n\n  TIPS:\n 1) The vegetables are optional. Yogurt rice tastes great with the seasoning alone.\n 2) If you want to take this dish for picnics or trips, and will not be serving it within 4 hours, instead of 2 cups of yogurt, add 1 cup yogurt and 1 cup milk. This will prevent the yogurt from becoming sour. You can do the same if making ahead for parties, and don’t want to refrigerate it. \n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="5n" recipeName="Mixed Vegetable Kurma" serves="6-8" ingredients="1 cup green beans, cut into 1-inch pieces\n 1 cup carrots, cut into small cubes\n 1 cup potatoes, cut into small cubes\n 1 cup onions, cut into thin, 1/2-inch pieces (optional)\n 1 1/2 cups plain yogurt (optional)\n 1/4 tsp garam masala powder (optional)\n Salt to taste\n 1-2 tsp vegetable oil\n 1 tbsp, cilantro (coriander leaves) for garnish\n\n  FOR MASALA:\n 2 tsp poppy seeds\n 8-10 cashew nuts\n 1/2 cup grated coconut, fresh or dry\n 5-6 green chillies (adjust to taste)\n" method="1) Cook the vegetables with just enough water and some salt in the microwave or pressure cooker. Do not overcook the vegetables.\n 2) Roast the poppy seeds for a couple of seconds.\n 3) Grind the poppy seeds, cashews, chillies, and coconut with 1/4 cup water to a smooth, liquid paste, and set aside.\n 4) Heat oil in a wide pan, add the onions and a little salt, and saute on low heat until they are translucent.\n 5) Add the ground masala, cooked vegetables,and some salt.\n 6) Whisk the yogurt and add it to the mixed-vegetable kurma.\n 7) Cover and cook the curry on low heat for about 8 minutes, stirring occasionally.\n 8) Add the garam masala powder and cook for 2 more minutes.\n 9) Garnish with chopped cilantro.\n 10)Serve the mixed-vegetable kurma hot with rice, roti, or rice noodles.\n\n  TIPS:\n 1) If you don’t want to use yogurt, grind the masala with 1 cup of water. Mash some of the potato pieces to thicken the gravy. Or make a paste with 1-tsp rice flour or corn starch, and add it to the vegetables. Cook until the gravy thickens and the raw smell of the flour is gone.\n 2) This curry also tastes great without onions! \n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="6n" recipeName="Paneer Potato Patties" serves="2 (makes 8)" ingredients="1 cup paneer (Indian cheese, grated)\n 1 cup potatoes, grated\n 1/2 cup carrots, grated\n 1/4-inch piece ginger, grated\n 1-2 green chillies, finely chopped (adjust to taste)\n 2 1/4 tbsp all-purpose flour (maida)\n 2 tsp rava (semolina, farina, cream of wheat)\n 2 tbsp cilantro (coriander leaves), finely chopped\n Salt to taste\n Vegetable oil for deep-frying\n" method="1) In a medium bowl, combine all the ingredients.\n 2) Divide the mixture into 8 portions, and make round patties with each portion, pressing tightly, so they don’t fall apart in the oil when frying.\n 3) Heat the oil in a frying pan, and drop each pattie gently into the oil and fry until golden.\n 4) Drain on a paper-towel and place on a wire rack immediately to cool for a few seconds.\n 5) Serve the paneer-potato patties plain or with plain yogurt, and a cup of hot tea or coffee.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="7n" recipeName="Paneer Spring Rolls" serves="6-8 (makes 12-15)" ingredients="1 cup wheat flour\n 1 cup corn flour\n Salt to taste\n Red chilli powder, a pinch\n Vegetable oil for deep-frying\n\n  FOR FILLING:\n 1/4 cup paneer (cottage cheese), grated\n 1/4 cup cabbage, shredded\n 1/4 cup carrot, grated\n 1/4 cup bell-pepper, cut into 1/2-inch long thin strips\n 1 tbsp peas, fresh or frozen\n 2 tbsp cilantro (coriander leaves), finely chopped\n 1 tsp chilli powder\n 2 tsp lime/lemon juice (optional)\n Salt to taste\n" method="1) In a mixing bowl, mix the flours along with a little salt and red chilli powder with enough water into a smooth dough. Brush with a little oil and cover and set aside.\n 2) Heat the oil in a skillet. If using fresh peas, saute the peas until almost tender.\n 3) Add the cabbage, carrot, and bell-pepper, along with salt and chilli powder and stir-fry for a minutes.\n 4) Add the paneer and stir for a couple of seconds. Remove in a plate and let cool to room temperature. Stir in the the lime juice and cilantro.\n 5) Divide the dough into 1-inch diameter balls. Take a dough ball and roll on a floured surface into a very thin roti/tortilla (the thinner, the better, so when fried they become crunchy.) Cut the edges out to make a large rectangle (about 5-6 inches long and 4-inches wide), and cut the roti into 2 squares. Place 2 tsp of the vegetable and paneer filling on a square roti and roll it. Seal the edges and repeat with the remaining square.\n 6) Heat the oil in a frying pan and fry the paneer spring rolls until lightly golden and place on a wire rack or phulka grill to cool.\n 7) Repeat with the remaining spring rolls.\n 8) Re-fry all the paneer spring rolls until golden and let cool a bit.\n 9) Serve the rolls warm with tea or coffee.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="8n" recipeName="Poha Bread Vada" serves="6 (16-18 vadas)" ingredients="2 cups poha (pressed rice, rice flakes)\n 3 slices bread, ground into bread crumbs\n 2 tbsp coarsely ground peanuts\n 3-4 green chillies, finely chopped\n 1/2 tsp red chilli powder\n 1 tsp lime juice\n 1/2 tsp sugar (optional)\n 4-5 tbsp coriander (cilantro) leaves, finely chopped\n Salt to taste\n Vegetable oil for deep frying\n" method="1) Soak poha for 5 minutes in water and then drain the water.\n 2) Add the bread crumbs and all the other ingredients and mix to form a firm dough. Add a little water if required.\n 3) Take a small ball of the mixture and make a pattie or vada, pressing the mixture firmly, so it doesn’t break apart in the oil when frying.\n 4) Heat vegetable oil in a deep-frying pan, and fry the vadas till golden brown and crisp.\n 5) Serve the poha-bread vadas hot, with ketchup or ginger chutney.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="9n" recipeName="Sabudani Kichdi" serves="4" ingredients="1 1/2 cups sabudana (sago-big or small pearl sago), soaked overnight in a little water, just enough to cover the sabudana\n 1 1/2 cups peanuts, roasted and husk removed\n 1 medium potato\n Turmeric powder, a pinch\n 1 tsp red chilli powder (reduce if you want the khichdi to be mild)\n Sugar, a pinch\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR SEASONING:\n 5-6 tsp vegetable oil\n 5-6 green chillies\n 2 tsp cumin seeds\n 6-7 curry leaves\n" method="1) Drain any excess water from the sabudana.\n 2) Grind the peanuts to a coarse powder, and add it to the sabudana, along with turmeric powder, red chilli powder, salt, and sugar, and keep it aside.\n 3) Cut the potatoes in small cubes.\n 4) Heat oil in a wide and shallow pan, and add cumin seeds. When they start turning brown, add green chillies and curry leaves, stir for a couple of seconds, and add the potatoes. Cover and cook on low heat for 2-3 minutes, until potatoes are soft, stirring occasionally.\n 5) Add the sabudana and mix well. Sprinkle a little water, cover and cook on medium heat 5-6 minutes or until the sabudana becomes translucent. Stir occasionally to make sure the sabudana doesn’t stick to the bottom of the pan.\n 6) Serve the sabudana khichdi hot, with plain yogurt if desired.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="10n" recipeName="Sabudani Vada" serves="4 (makes 8-10)" ingredients="1 cup sabudana (sago)\n Soaked overnight in a little water\n Just enough to cover the sabudana\n 2 tbsp peanuts, roasted and husk removed\n 1 medium potato, boiled and peeled, and mashed\n Turmeric powder, a pinch\n 1/4 tsp red chilli powder (adjust to taste)\n 2-4 green chillies, finely chopped\n 2 tbsp cilantro (coriander leaves), finely chopped\n Salt to taste\n Vegetable oil for deep-frying\n " method="1) Drain any excess water from the sabudana.\n 2) Grind the peanuts to a coarse powder, and add it to the sabudana, along with turmeric powder, red chilli powder, salt, mashed potato, green chillies, and cilantro, and mix well.\n 3) Make small balls with this mixture (a little smaller than a golf ball), flatten them a bit, and set aside.\n 4) Heat oil, and gently drop a small ball of the sabudana to test the temperature of the oil. If the ball floats to the top right away, the oil is hot enough. Fry the sabudana vadas until golden brown.\n 5) Serve the sabudana vadas plain or with ketchup, and a hot cup of tea or coffee.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="11n" recipeName="Samosa" serves="4" ingredients="FOR SAMOSA PASTRY:\n 3 cups maida ( all-purpose flour)\n 3 tsp yogurt\n 1 1/2 tbsp butter, melted\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR SAMOSA FILLING (POTATO CURRY):\n 4 large potatoes, boiled, peeled, and crumbled into small pieces\n 1/2 cup peas\n 7-8 green chillies, finely chopped\n 1 tsp cumin seeds\n 1/4 tsp coriander seeds\n 1 tsp coriander powder\n 1/2 tsp garam masala\n 1 tsp raw mango aamchur powder or 4 tbsp lime juice\n 1/2 tsp red chilli powder\n 4-5 tbsp cilantro (coriander) leaves, finely chopped\n Salt to taste\n Vegetable oil for deep frying\n" method="FOR THE SAMOSA PASTRY:\n Mix the flour with yogurt, salt and butter. Sprinkle a little water at a time and make a stiff dough. Refrigerate the dough for 10-15 minutes.\n\n  FOR THE SAMOSA CURRY:\n 1) In a pan, heat 3 tbsp of oil and add the cumin seeds. As they start spluttering, add coriander seeds, green chillies, peas, garam masala, coriander powder, chilli powder, and mango powder and fry for a few seconds.\n 2) Add the potatoes and salt to taste. Mix well and cook for 2 minutes and then add the chopped cilantro. If you’re using lime juice, instead of mango powder, add the juice after removing curry from the heat. Cool for 5 minutes.\n\n  TO MAKE THE SAMOSA:\n 1) Divide the dough into small portions, (golf-ball size). On a lightly floured surface, roll a ball into an oval shape 7-8? in diameter, a little thicker than for a roti or tortilla.\n 2) Cut the oval into 2 pieces with a knife. Apply water to the edges, fold it into a cone and seal the edges. Fill the cone with the potato curry/filling, and seal the top edge by gently pulling together the edges, and place them on a plate, top edge down. Repeat with the remaining dough.\n 3) Heat oil in a deep frying pan, and fry the samosas on medium-low heat until golden brown. Drain the excess oil on a paper towel.\n 4) Serve the samosas hot with mint-coriander chutney and tamarind dip, and tea or coffee.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="12n" recipeName="Spicy Almonds" serves="3" ingredients="1 lb whole almonds\n 2 tbsp vegetable oil\n 1 tbsp garam masala powder\n 1/2 tbsp amchur (mango powder)\n 1/2 tsp red chilli powder\n Salt to taste\n" method="1) Preheat the oven to 375°F.\n 2) In a large bowl, add all the dry ingredients and mix well.\n 3) Add the almonds and sprinkle the oil and toss well until the almonds are coated well with the spice mix.\n 4) Spread the almonds on a baking sheet, and bake for 5-8 minutes.\n 5) Remove from the oven and turn the almonds to make sure they get toasted evenly and don’t get burnt.\n 6) Place them back in the oven and bake them for 5-8 minutes more or until golden brown.\n 7) Remove the spicy almonds from the oven and let cool completely before serving.\n\n  TIP: Store the almonds in an airtight container in a cool, dry place to keep them fresh for up to a month. \n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="13n" recipeName="Spicy Puffed Rice" serves="3" ingredients="6 cups puffed rice\n 1 medium onion, finely chopped\n 1 medium tomato, cut into small cubes\n 2 green chillies, finely chopped\n 1 1/2 tsp mustard seeds\n Asafoetida (hing), a pinch\n 4 tbsp coriander (cilantro) leaves, finely chopped\n 1/2 tsp red chilli powder\n 1 tsp dhania-jeera (coriander seeds and cumin seed powder)\n 2 tbsp dalia (roasted, split chickpeas,\n without the husk), coarsely powdered\n Salt to taste\n 5-6 tsp vegetable oil\n" method="1) Soak the puffed rice in water for 5 minutes, and then drain all the water, pressing the rice lightly.\n 2) Heat oil in a pan, add asafoetida and mustard seeds. When the seeds start popping, add the chillies, onions, and a little salt, and saute for 2-3 minutes. Cover and cook until the onions are translucent.\n 3) Add the tomatoes and saute for 2 minutes.\n 4) Add the dhania-jeera powder and red chilli powder, and saute for a minute.\n 5) Add the puffed rice, dali powder, and salt and mix well. Cover and cook on medium heat for 5 minutes till the puffed rice is cooked.\n 6) Add the chopped coriander leaves.\n 7) Serve the spicy puffed rice hot.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="14n" recipeName="Spicy Rice Noodles" serves="3-4" ingredients="2 cups rice noodles\n 6 cups of water\n\n  FOR CURRY:\n 1/2 cup green beans, finely cut\n 1.2 cup carrots, finely cut\n 1/2 cup onions (optional)\n 1/ cup peas, fresh or frozen\n 1 tsp coriander-cumin (dhania-jeera) powder\n 1 tsp red chilli powder (adjust to taste)\n 4-5 tsp vegetable oil\n 1/2 tsp cumin seeds (jeera)\n 1/2 tsp mustard seeds (rai)\n 2 red chillies broken into a couple pieces\n 3 tsp dalia powder (roasted chickpea flour) or peanut powder\n 1/4 tsp tamarind paste\n 1 tsp sugar\n 2 tbsp cilantro (coriander leaves), finely chopped\n Salt to taste\n" method="1) Take a deep pan, add water and bring it to a boil.\n 2) Add the rice noodles and cook for 4-5 minutes until cooked but not mushy.\n 3) Drain, add a cup of cold water, drain again, and cool.\n 4) In a microwavable bowl, add the cut vegetables and sprinkle some salt and water. Cover and cook for about 5 minutes or until vegetables are tender. Let cool. Or boil separately with some water and salt.\n 5) Heat oil in a shallow pan or skillet. Add the cumin and mustard seeds. As the seeds start to pop, add the red chillies and fry until chillies are browned a bit.\n 6) Add the onions along with some salt. Saute on low heat until they are translucent.\n 7) Add the coriander-cumin powder and red chilli powder and saute for 2 minutes.\n 8) Add the boiled vegetables, tamarind paste, sugar, dalia or peanut powder along with 1/2 cup water. Cover and cook on low heat until the gravy has thickened and the raw flavor of the dalia is gone. Remove the spicy rice noodles from heat.\n 9) Add the rice noodles, a little at a time until you have the proportion of noodles and veggies the way you want. Add salt as needed. Mix well and saute on low heat until the noodles have absorbed the gravy and are well-coated.\n 10)Garnish the spicy rice noodles with chopped cilantro and serve immediately.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="15n" recipeName="Spinach Vada" serves="4" ingredients="1 cup urad dal (black gram), soaked for 40 minutes\n 1 cup spinach, finely chopped\n 1 onion, medium, finely chopped\n 7-8 green chillies, finely chopped\n Salt to taste\n Vegetable oil for deep frying\n" method="1) Drain the water from the dal and in a blender, grind it into a thick, coarse batter, adding only a little water. The batter should not be watery.\n 2) Add the chopped spinach, onions, green chillies, and salt, and mix well.\n 3) Heat oil in a deep frying pan.\n 4) Keep water handy in a bowl. Moisten your palm and fingers with the water, and take a small ball (golf-sized) of batter and place it on your palm. Flatten it a little and and make a hole in the center, as in a doughnut. Drop it into the pan.\n 5) Repeat with the remaining batter, and fry the vadas till golden brown on medium heat.\n 6) Serve the spinach vadas hot, with tamarind dip or chutney and beverage of your choice.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="16n" recipeName="Stuffed Egg Plant" serves="3-4" ingredients="8 thin eggplants, about 2 1/2 inches long\n (Italian eggplant works well;if you have long eggplants cut in half)\n 5-7 tsp vegetable oil for shallow-frying\n\n  FOR FILLING:\n 1 cup onions, finely chopped\n 1/4 cup besan (chickpea flour)\n 1-1 1/2 ts red chilli powder\n 1/4 tsp turmeric powder\n 1 tsp vegetable oil\n Salt to taste\n" method="1) Wash the eggplant, remove the stem, and make double slits on both ends.\n 2) In a small bowl, mix the onions, besan, turmeric, red chilli powders, salt and oil.\n 3) Take a little of this mixture and stuff the eggplants, both ends, and set aside.\n 4) In a wok or skillet, heat 5-6 tsp oil. Lower the heat and place each eggplant carefully, sprinkle some salt and water and cover and cook for 4-5 minutes, stirring occasionally, until tender.\n 5) Remove the lid and saute the stuffed eggplant on medium heat until nicely browned and crunchy on all sides.\n 6) Serve the stuffed eggplant with rice, plain dal, and ghee.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="17n" recipeName="Sweet Potato Curry" serves="4" ingredients="3 medium sweet potatoes, lightly peeled and cut into medium-sized cubes and boiled or cooked in the microwave\n 1/2 inch piece of ginger, finely chopped\n 6-7 green chillies, slit and cut into small pieces\n 6-7 curry leaves\n 1/4 cup freshly grated (or dry) coconut\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR SEASONING:\n 1 tbsp chana dal (split bengal gram)\n 5-6 tsp vegetable oil\n Asafoetida (hing), a pinch\n 1/2 tsp turmeric powder\n 1 1/2 tsp mustard (rai) seeds\n" method="1) Heat the oil in a wide pan on medium heat. Add the asafoetida and chana dal. As the dal starts to brown, add the mustard seeds. As the seeds start to splutter, add the chillies and ginger and fry for a few seconds and then add the turmeric powder and curry leaves.\n 2) Add the boiled and cubed sweet potatoes and salt to taste. Mix well and cover and cook for two minutes. Add the grated cocnut and stir for a minute or two.\n 3) Serve the sweet potato curry hot with plain white rice and a dollop of ghee (clarified butter).\n  TIPS:\n To save time, boil the sweet potatoes in the pressure cooker for 2-3 whistles or use the potato setting in the microwave. The sweet potato should not be too soft.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="18n" recipeName="Tindora Tomato Gravy Curry" serves="4" ingredients="4 cups tindora, cut into 1-inch long thin strips\n 2 1/2 cups tomatoes, cut into medium cubes\n Turmeric powder, a pinch\n 4-6 curry leaves\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR MASALA:\n 4 tsp sesame seeds\n 4-5 red chillies\n 1 tbsp coconut, freshly grated or dried\n 3 tsp roasted chickpeas/dalia\n\n  FOR SEASONING:\n 1 tsp vegetable oil\n 1/2 tsp mustard seeds\n 1 red chilli\n 4-5 curry leaves\n" method="1) Wash the cut tindora well, removing as many seeds as you can. Cook the tindora with a little salt and water in the microwave for about 6 minutes or until tender.\n 2) In a small pan, roast the sesame seeds on medium heat until aromatic, and set aside. Roast the red chillies and set aside.\n 3) In a small grinder (coffee grinder works fine), grind the sesame seeds, chillies, coconut and dalia into a coarse powder.\n 4) Heat oil in a medium skillet, and add the mustard seeds and fry until they start to pop. Add the red chilli and fry for a few seconds. Then add the curry leaves and fry for a second. Add the tindora (along with any remaining water), tomatoes, and turmeric powder and salt if needed, and cook on medium heat for 3-4 minutes.\n 5) Stir in the masala powder over the tindora, and cook on low heat until the tindora-tomato gravy curry thickens, and remove from heat.\n 6) Garnish with a little coconut and serve the tindora-tomato gravy curry with plain rice.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="19n" recipeName="Vangibath" serves="4-6" ingredients="2 cups rice (jasmine rice or any other non-sticky rice)\n 2 cups, eggplants (long or small round ones), cut into 1-inch pieces and immersed in a bowl of water to prevent discoloring\n 6-8 tsp vegetable oil\n 5-6 curry leaves\n Salt to taste\n\n  FOR MASALA:\n Use the store-bought Vangi Bhath powder\n (or)\n 4 tsp coriander seeds (dhania)\n 3 tsp urad dal (split black gram)\n 4 tsp chana dal (split bengal gram)\n 6 tbsp dry, grated coconut\n 1/4 tsp cinnamon powder (optional)\n 14-16 red chillies (adjust to taste)\n Asafoetida (hing), a pinch\n" method="1) Heat oil in a small pan, and fry the coriander, urad dal, chana dal, and red chillies until golden brown and set aside to cool. Add the grated coconut and fry until light brown.\n 2) When all the masala ingredients are cool, grind these with some hing into a coarse powder.\n 3) In the same pan, fry the cashewnuts till golden brown and set aside.\n 4) Cook the rice in a rice cooker or pressure cooker with 4 cups of water. Let the rice cool.\n 5) Heat 6 tsp oil in a wide skillet, and add the hing and curry leaves and fry for a couple of seconds.\n 6) Add the eggplant and salt. Saute the vangi or eggplant on medium heat, until it’s cooked and sauteed well.\n 7) Add the vangi bhath masala you just powdered (4-5 tsp) or 4-5 tsp of the store-bought powder, and fry for a couple of seconds.\n 8) Add the cooked rice along with some salt and mix well. Add more masala if needed.\n 9) Saute the rice and eggplant for a few minutes until all flavors are combined.\n 10)Mix in the cashewnuts, and serve the vangi bhath hot with some papadams.\n" />
    <RecipeDetails id="20n" recipeName="Vegetable Vermicelli Upma" serves="4-5" ingredients="1 1/2 cups vermicelli (MTR semiya or other brand)\n 1/2 cup onions, finely choppedn\n 1/2 cup carrots, cut into fine cubes\n 1/2 cup bell-peppers (capsicum), cut into small cubes\n 1/2 cup tomatoes, cut into small cubes\n 1/4 cup peas (optional)\n 1/2 tsp rasam powder (MTR or other brand)\n 2 tbsp cilantro (coriander leaves), chopped\n 3 cups water\n\n  FOR SEASONING:\n 7-8 tsp vegetable oil\n 1 1/2 tsp urad dal (black gram)\n 1/2 tsp mustard seeds\n 5-6 green chillies, finely chopped\n" method="1) If you’re using long (angel hair) pasta or vermicelli, cut it into 1/4 inch pieces. Roast the vermicelli or pasta in 2 tsp of oil for a couple of minutes, until brown. This prevents the upma from becoming sticky. You can skip this step, if you like.\n 2) Heat oil in a shallow pan, and add the urad dal and mustard seeds. When the seeds start to splutter, add the add green chillies, ginger, curry leaves, and onions, bell-peppers, and carrots, along with some salt.\n 3) Cover and cook for 3-4 minutes on low heat, stirring occasionally, until onions become translucent, and other vegetables are cooked.\n 4) Add the tomatoes and peas and saute for 2 minutes. Then add the water, and cover. When the water comes to a boil, add some more salt, cilantro leaves, and rasam powder, and vermicelli.\n 5) Cover and cook the vegetable vermicelli upma on low heat for 5-7 minutes, stirring occasionally. Remove the lid and cook for 2 more minutes until all the water evaporates.\n 6) Serve the vegetable vermicelli upma hot and either plain or with chutney powder or pickle of your choice.\n" />
</resources>